Heat. Heat.
That's
heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
Welcome Living Mana Church family. We're
so happy to have you here with us today
on this beautiful Sabbath day. It's such
a blessing to be able to take one day
out of the week, a 24-hour period, and
just spend with God and with each other.
So, the Sabbath is a blessing uh from
God, and we're just so happy that you
are here with us today. Please put in
the chat where you're viewing from so we
can say hello and welcome to you. If
this is the first time you're visiting
Living Man Church, please put in the
chat where you're viewing from and a one
um and so that we can know that this is
your very first time. and um viewing
audience and members, please welcome our
guests who put in the the chat where
they're viewing from and definitely
welcome our first time viewers. Again,
welcome and we are happy that you are
here.
>> Amen. And we want to just uh invite you
if you have not yet uh liked the ch u
the channel uh or subscribed, please do
so now and invite people share share
this link. let people know that uh we
are on
>> and that the service has begun
>> and uh just invite them friends,
enemies, whoever all need to hear the
word of God.
>> Yes. So
>> invite your friends or family members to
church today and you know living man of
church makes it so easy for you to
invite and it makes it so easy for them
to attend as well. They can attend in
the comforts of their own home. So,
please put in the chat where you're
viewing from. And again, if it's a if
it's your first time, please put a one
in the chat. We are just happy that you
are here today. Want to say that we had
a wonderful communion last night. It's a
blessing to be able to do communion with
all of you. We are asked, well, we were
just asked when we were in Australia,
how do you do communion? And we were
able to explain how we we do it. we're
able to uh do the bread and wine and
even do the uh footwashing and we have a
whole service and program. So, it's
beautiful uh that we're able to do that
together with our brothers and sisters
from all around the world. So, it's a
blessing.
>> Amen.
>> And we have
>> Oh, go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Well, we were going to talk about the
baptism.
>> No, but go ahead. And we do have a
baptism as well that's coming up on the
15th of November.
>> Uh we're going to be in North Carolina
and we have several people being
baptized.
>> Exciting.
>> And so that's another question people
often ask. Well, how do you do baptisms
in an online church?
>> Um yeah, we will we have had people come
out to where we are to be baptized and
we have gone
>> travel to them as well.
>> Yeah.
>> And so if you're wanting to be baptized,
uh you'll find out more information on
how to do that. Um, but Pastor Myers
will baptize you. So, um, it's the
online church doesn't stop doesn't stop
anything.
>> Amen.
>> We can still do everything that other
churches do, I like to say, and more.
But we get to do all of that. But I have
a t-shirt message, and this is not new.
You guys have seen this many times, but
there's that's always a good reminder.
>> Love like Jesus five times. That's
right. Love like Jesus. Love like Jesus.
Love like Jesus. Love like Jesus. Just
be nice.
Simple. Just be nice. Jesus was nice and
loving. Be nice and loving to to others.
Just
think about what Jesus would do in a
situation and do that.
>> Amen.
>> And if you're if you're confused, pray
and ask him, Lord, give me wisdom how I
should what I should do in this
situation. and he will always give you
the right answer that's going to cause
you to love like him or move like him.
And um it's just really not rocket
science.
>> Yep.
>> To be a Christian,
>> just love like Jesus. Love others like
Jesus how he loves them and love
yourself like Jesus loves you.
>> Um I go through that in with my clients
in therapy a lot. Not not I don't say
love yourself like Jesus. Some of my my
clients are not Christians,
>> but I put that principle out there that
they should love themselves.
>> Um and then when you love yourself, it's
easier to treat other people in the way
that you need to treat them
>> um because you're loving yourself.
>> Yeah. Um I think that love like Jesus re
a Christian is one who is like Christ.
That's really what it means to be to be
like Christ. So, it really is very
simple. And um I think when you love
others
>> um and when you love God,
>> you have a true appreciation of
uh of how God sees you.
>> Yes.
>> Right. And I think a lot of people don't
have that value. They don't see that
value in themselves that God sees in
them. So, you know, love yourself in the
worldly terms, in a worldly way,
>> can be a very negative thing.
>> Right.
>> But loving yourself, you know, there's a
lot of people that love themselves and
love themselves over other people.
>> Right. So, love yourself like Jesus.
That's right. Loving loving you like
Jesus is not putting you above anybody
else.
>> It's it's just you love yourself.
There's more.
>> You understand your value in God's eyes.
Yes, because we have the reason why we
have
>> so much depression
>> and even anxiety
>> is because um
>> we're not loving ourselves like Jesus
loves us
>> and we don't see the value,
>> right?
Exactly.
>> Um
>> yeah, could go on and on and on,
>> but
>> yeah, love yourself like Jesus loves
you.
So, we're going to go ahead and jump
into our Sabbath school.
>> Yes, that's what we're going to do. And
we'll pray first.
>> Yeah. And we are I don't think we've
talked about this yet, but we are going
to be going through the Christian art of
war.
>> We're continuing.
>> Yeah. We're in chapter 4.
>> And um for those of you that are like,
"Well, where'd you get this book from?"
Uh it is a book that I wrote and we it
was written
>> between 15 and 17 years ago. We haven't
we haven't sat down a long time ago.
>> But the book is still very relevant.
>> It's my favorite.
>> Oh,
>> it's gonna be it's relevant
>> until the day Jesus comes. It's
relevant.
>> It's so relevant for the Christian.
>> And you can get um each chapter as we go
through it on mighty networks. So if you
have are not on mighty networks, I'll be
sharing how you can do that at the
beginning of divine worship service. Um,
and we want you to get we want you to be
on Mighty Networks, not just to download
the book for other reasons, but but for
Sabbath school purposes so that you can
download the chapter so that you can be
reading and studying right along with
us.
>> Amen. So, we have our guests. We're
picking up in chapter 4.
>> We're dealing with the fruit of the
spirit. And um the last in our last uh
last Sabbath, we got up to peace.
>> Yes.
>> And we only read the title. the title.
>> No war, no peace. No war, no peace. And
we spent the rest of time just talking
about the title.
>> That's a t-shirt, I think. Have I seen
that as a t-shirt before?
>> That is a t-shirt. Huh?
>> That's a t-shirt I need to get then.
>> Yeah,
>> that's already been made. Okay. Um, but
let's pray and then we'll bring on our
guest.
>> All right. Heavenly Father, we just uh
come before you at this time, Lord,
asking that you would uh guide us, Lord,
as we continue our discussion on uh
fighting the Christian art of war. The
greatest battle that we face, Lord, is a
battle against our own selves.
>> So Lord, please uh just um speak through
us, speak through our panel.
And Lord, may the words that we share um
be a blessing for those who listen, for
those who will watch. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen. Amen. Amen.
All right. So, we'd like to welcome our
panelists. Welcome, guys.
>> Happy Sabbath.
>> Michaela Sabbath
>> and Kashie. So good to see all of you.
Happy Sabbath to you, too. All right.
So, are you guys ready for peace?
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Yes. You ready to go? I know Michaela is
because Michaela, I remember you ended
and you said, "I'm gonna save what I
have to say till next week." So,
>> Oh, yes.
>> Yeah. Yeah. But you know what? I don't
forget. That's one thing about
>> your pastor's wife is my memory is
pretty good. I have to say
>> I remember. Um so I think we might Well,
you know what? Pastor Myers is actually
going to I think read
>> Yeah. the opener and then um the
beginning of that chapter and then
>> yeah and I think what I'm going to do
because what we've been doing in the
past is I would read a sentence and then
we would stop and just not move any
further for the rest of the class. So
I'm actually going to read through the
entire piece section. Okay?
that way. Yeah. That way we kind of go
through the whole thing and then we can
go back
>> and just kind of comment on, you know,
different sections of it and then
hopefully
>> we won't be on piece for like three
weeks.
>> Okay, let's do that. And while you're um
getting that uh ready to go, just want
to let the viewing audience know that
you are part of this study. So, please
put your comments um in the chat. Even
questions, put that in the chat. Uh we'd
like to know what you are thinking as we
are going through uh this study, the
Christian art of war. And I'm letting
you know already Michaela, I'm going to
come to you first after pastor uh is
done. And I'm just excited to continue
this study.
>> All right. So, are we ready?
>> We're ready.
>> So, um no war, no peace. No war, no
peace. Thankfully, we got past that last
week. We just stopped right there.
>> That was just a heading.
>> But, um, let's go ahead and, uh, I'll
begin to read. And it's just, it's not
long at all, but I think it's
significant. So,
>> uh, the spirit of peace is another vital
spirit for the warrior for the war
against self. There is a popular saying,
freedom is not free. Likewise, on this
side of eternity, there can be no peace
without war. Yet, the war we must fight
is the war to maintain our peace in the
midst of the angry storms of life.
>> The greatest warrior is the one who can
maintain his peace in the midst of
temptation and trial. Jesus, the prince
of peace, rested in the middle of the
storm, revealing an uncanny mastery of
this spirit of peace.
>> Matthew 8:24 is quoted, "And behold,
there arose a great tempest in the sea,
in so much that the ship was covered
with waves, but he was asleep."
>> I think I've done a sermon before where
I talked about the pillow.
>> Yes,
>> the pillow.
>> It was called the pillow.
>> I don't know if I preached that here at
Living.
>> It definitely was. No, no, no, no. I
need to preach that.
>> So yeah, don't don't give it all away
because when you repeat it, they're
going to know it was a repeat and it
wasn't a
>> the pillow. The pillow.
>> But he always mixes it up so it's not
it's true.
>> His ability his ability to rest in the
storm he offers to us through the
spirit.
>> He says, "Come unto me all ye that labor
and are heavy laden, and I will give you
rest." This resting in the spirit of
peace is of invaluable worth in the
warfare against self. How often have you
been helplessly catapulted by self into
the middle of a storm of angry words and
emotions, leading all involved to be
tossed to and fro on the waves of
unrighteousness?
>> In mastering the spirit of peace, you
reveal a mastery of and over the
so-called unpredictable elements of
human nature.
>> And that's, you know, we're not talking
about nature now. We're talking about
the storms of human nature
>> that often bring that spirit of unrest.
>> We are given a command to be under the
domination of peace. Colossians 3:15
says, "Let the peace of God rule in your
hearts in the which also you are called
in one body and be thankful."
That is let your heart be dominated by
peace so that no storm of words however
strong can move you out of your place.
>> Jesus held his peace during the mockery
of a trial that would take his life.
Matthew 263.
>> Mercy.
>> Amazingly enough, it is through
maintaining our peace that we bruise and
will bruise the head of the serpent.
Romans 16:20 says, "And the God of peace
shall bruise Satan under your feet
shortly." Whenever we hold our peace,
Satan's mind is blown.
The Bible tells us, "Great peace have
they which love thy law, and nothing
shall offend them." Psalm 119:165.
Peace is our defense from offense. It is
the spirit that maintained protects us
from the trap of retaliation.
>> The trap
>> the spirit of peace then may be likened
unto our defense system. Our war in turn
becomes the war to hold our tongues to
remain calm and collected. How great a
war this is. we win or lose in
proportion to our mastery or failure to
master this spirit.
>> How important then that we as warriors
receive, meditate on, and live out this
spirit of peace? How important is it
that we master this dying art? Many are
unwilling to fight the war for peace.
But if we would have peace, we must
aggressively fight for it. For on this
side of eternity, there can be no peace
without fighting to maintain it.
>> This is the spirit of the warrior.
>> That was I'm glad you read the whole
thing, but wow, that was so
powerful. There were so many points. Um,
but I Michaela, I I said I was going to
you first, but there were so many good
um good points in there. like okay right
after this Michaela
he because you said in there that that
Jesus
taught us how to respond like basically
not respond while being beaten and
mocked and all of these things and
people taunting him you know with his
with their words
>> and he taught us how to hold our peace
because he did it
>> when you are in that type of situation
when somebody's trying to get you to
respond with an angry word or
>> and it's not even they're trying. They
don't even they may not even realize
they're trying,
>> but they're trying.
>> Yeah. Right. But
>> yeah.
>> Okay. Either way, got you. Yeah. But to
respond like Jesus,
love like Jesus, even when you're
openly being mocked or someone's trying
to get you or even if the person doesn't
know that's what they're doing, but you
know, but it but it is triggering you.
Jesus has taught us how to respond
>> and that's not respond.
>> Yeah. The the battle is to hold your
peace.
>> Um and this almost sounds like counter
intuitive counter to like everything
that a fighter would do. But I I'll say
this,
>> it's counter to everything that's in our
flesh.
>> Yeah.
>> It's it's a it's a
>> it's a very strange principle, but the
martial artist, the true martial artist,
>> prides himself on never getting into a
fight.
>> Yes. You've told me that before.
>> Right. So they spend all their life
training,
>> but they almost look at
>> not to fight. Yeah.
>> If someone can r them up to get into a
fight, it's almost as if
>> they already lost the battle over
themselves.
>> Mercy. Just stop right there. Just stop.
Everybody just stop. Everybody stop what
you're doing.
>> Say it again. Say it again.
>> I don't remember how I said it.
>> That was a good one, though. That was
really good. That blew my mind.
>> So, you said that
if they can get them to respond and
fight, they feel like they've already
lost the battle.
>> They may have they may have won the
physical fight, but they lost the inner
battle of maintaining
peace.
>> I know the martial art people would
never say that these principles are from
the Bible, but those principles are from
the Bible. I just don't know it because
that is so like that's what happens,
you know, when we respond. We think we
win the fight like, you know, oh, I won
the fight. I told you. You actually
lost.
>> You lost.
>> You absolutely lost.
>> Wow.
>> I know you have something to say.
Uh, well, first off, like probably
sounds weird, but I pretty sure peace is
my favorite of the spirit. Like you can
just see how
>> doesn't sound weird. essential.
Essential it is because like so many
things in life just seem like they
directly attack peace and
>> yes
>> like
just different things people struggle
with. Whether it's stress, whether it's
oh all this stuff, like it's hard to
live without peace, let alone fight
without a source of peace because
>> like in the middle of
>> the moment of whatever stress is
happening, what whatever depression,
whatever
struggle is happening, it's really hard
to
emit a sense of peace and have that
sense of peace in you.
>> Um,
which that's what we need to fight.
>> Yes.
>> Like, yeah.
>> Amen.
>> Start.
>> You know what? I I have to say this. You
have the cutest dog that I think
>> this is the second time she's
>> I'm sorry, but I'm listening to what
you're saying and it was beautifully.
Amen to that. But that has to be the
cutest,
sweetest. I keep thinking it's a stuffed
animal. You sure? Okay. He just doesn't.
Wow. And he just lays there like, "Yeah,
she's talking to a whole bunch of
people, but I'm just going to chill
right here. That's a That's He looks
like a teddy bear." And he's a dog.
>> So,
>> okay,
>> since we're talking about the dog.
>> Sorry.
>> Uh, see how he's sleep on that bed and
he's just at peace. Now peace that is
you know I mean of course there's not
chaos happening around him right now but
>> it's that kind of peace right
>> that Jesus
>> even though the whole world is watch
>> I know we may as we may as well use the
object lesson yeah we may as well just
use the object lesson
>> uh that's the kind of piece right that's
the the the rest and it looks like he's
resting on a comforter and I guess I
just got to give my my a peace sermon
away a little bit. But you know, that's
what a comforter is.
>> That's what the comforter is.
>> Amen.
>> The comforter,
>> not not talking about the thing on your
bed, but the comforter,
>> it allows us to rest in peace.
>> Right.
>> So Lord, how do I get that?
>> How do I get that pillow? How do I get
that comforter
>> that allows me to like Jesus sleep in
the midst of chaos, sleep, rest in the
midst of the storm
>> and know that that God is walking with
me because the devil, right, he wants us
to have no peace.
>> Yes,
>> there is no peace for the wicked.
How can I steal their peace? How can I
take away the comforter from them?
Because if I can take away the
comforter, then your peace is gone. And
that's the battle.
>> Now, correct me if I'm wrong. Was he
really? We You called it a pillow, but
wasn't it a stone? No, it wasn't a
stone.
>> No,
>> I feel like I thought I heard that the
pill that it wasn't like you know, we
think pillow like what we have. And I
Okay, if I'm wrong, I'm wrong. But
you sure?
Where'd I get that from?
>> So, and he was in the hinder part of the
ship asleep
>> on a pillow.
>> On a pillow.
>> I like to emphasize that. Okay.
>> Because
>> I don't know where I got that. It was
like we would have looked at it like a
pillow, but it was really like a stone
cuz I was about to make an application.
But
>> you're probably talking about uh like
Jacob.
>> Okay.
>> When he was Yeah. All right. But but
still, I mean, that's neither here nor
there.
uh the the the idea when the text says
talking about Jesus being in the storm,
right?
>> And it's almost like
>> you could have just said he was asleep
in the boat
>> in the midst of a storm. That would have
been like it that would have been like
wow how. But it's almost like just for
emphasis they put
>> on a pillow
>> in the midst of a storm.
Almost like
Satan, in case you thought you were
scaring Jesus, not only was he asleep,
but he was sleeping on a pillow. He was
comfortable.
>> Yeah.
>> Sleeping.
>> It was almost like he was um mocking
Satan like, "Oh, you got a storm boy?
I'm just going to go to sleep
>> because you're not as powerful as my
God."
>> Can you imagine sleeping in the presence
of your enemies?
>> Like, you're wrong. I couldn't.
>> No, you're really not getting to me.
You're trying to get to me, but you're
not getting to me.
>> Yeah,
>> that's that's something I can teach in
therapy, too. Like to actually
>> in couples therapy, for sure.
>> Like, don't respond
uh
to don't like to triggers.
>> Hold your peace.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> All right. We've been hogging it. So,
y'all y'all jump in. There's
>> Yes.
>> Well, I mean, I feel like you you kind
of said all that I wanted to say on the
topic.
>> I saw it on your face.
>> I think
>> Say it in your mind.
>> Okay. So,
Okay. Well, I mean, what was what stood
out to me from what pastor said was that
Jesus was asleep on the comforter. And I
was like, "Oh my goodness." Because that
is literally what I was going at. I was
thinking, "Oh my goodness, he's asleep
in the storm. He's resting." You know,
it's like in the middle of the storm, he
has rest. And then you brought in the
comforter. And I was like, "That's where
he's got it from." Like I was like, for
us in our in our situation, it's like,
okay, when there's a storm of human
nature going on around us, we can be at
rest on the comforter. in the comforter
>> and that was just like, oh my goodness,
>> I can't.
>> Yeah. And I mean, so you think about it,
Melinda, like the purpose of a comforter
is what? I know, you know, we're always
set to comfort, but why do people get a
comforter?
>> To be warm,
>> to be covered,
>> to be covered.
>> You want a comforter to cover you.
That's what we use a comforter for.
>> And to be more comfortable.
>> To be to be comfortable and to be
covered. So,
>> and when you're comfortable, you It's
You have peace.
>> Yeah. And you sleep.
>> And you sleep.
>> You can sleep. When you're covered and
you're comfortable and you're at peace
and you're warm.
>> Yeah. Now I can sleep. Right.
>> How is Jesus comfortable and warm
>> in a wet storm
>> in the rain?
There's a there's a powerful
lesson there
>> that
when we look at it, we say, "Lord, teach
me."
Cuz I'm going through the stor the
storms of life all the time. I'm going
through the storms of,
>> you know, human passion, the storms of
anger, the storms of strife, people's
storms coming at me and my storms that I
can't control. Mhm.
>> Lord, how do I learn how to be
comfortable in the midst of the crisis?
>> Yeah.
>> I don't want to cut anybody off. Does
anybody else want to say something?
Okay. Because the crisis doesn't have to
be like this big
this huge thing. The crisis could be
just use an example um earlier this past
week like
everything my my car broke down
never made it like waiting there for
three hours
>> it was cold I was hungry
um
>> yeah and then I get home and
>> and it was storming
>> and it was storming and I only had a
sweater on.
It was actually but I was praying to
God,
calling you,
calling other family and feeling and
just but and and having experiencing
having peace even in that situation was
tempted to be like frustrated because
there was still a lot to do uh that
evening. But it worked out.
>> It worked out.
>> It worked out and I didn't lose my
peace.
>> Yeah. tended to.
>> Yeah,
>> for sure.
>> The key thing is we have to remember
that God has us covered.
>> That's the point,
>> right? If I can keep that in mind,
>> God's got me
>> covered, then all right,
>> I have peace.
>> Cuz when you're wearing a com when you
got a comforter on you, it kind of
cushions, you know, like
>> it cushions stuff. You know what I'm
saying? It's like
>> if if you get hit with a comforter on,
the comforter abs is absorbing
right
>> that that blow.
>> Oh, this is getting like bigger and
bigger. My goodness.
>> So, are we walking around
with a comforter on us
>> or are we walking around with no
comforter?
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
>> Why you always resting? Oh, man. This
comforter, it's just you don't
understand.
>> It keeps me.
>> It keeps me. And the comforter is the
covering of Christ's righteousness.
>> Yes.
>> It's a thick robe.
>> It's not a thin robe.
>> It's that
>> Christ righteousness that he gives to
you in the storm so you have peace.
>> Yeah.
>> And you stay warm.
>> Yeah. From the attacks of the enemy.
>> Does anyone have any thoughts?
>> Yeah. When you know that you have that
um
when you know that you have that that
comforter, you know, you can rest easy.
You can rest easy knowing that you know
anything that happens and um
you might get that urge to retaliate,
but then you're able to check and see
what could happen as a result of you
retaliating.
And
>> that urge quickly turns into compassion.
It quickly turns into a joy of victory
over that initial urge.
>> And you enjoy the peace even more.
>> It just you sink into it even more. It
just becomes deeper.
>> Yep.
>> Absolutely. and to be able to fall
asleep. You know, you have to have
if I'm stressed or worried about
something,
>> I'm I have a very hard time falling
asleep. I shouldn't be stressed or
worried. Okay? So, I'm not
>> giving everything to God at that moment.
So, I'm stressed and worried.
>> And if I do fall asleep, I don't sleep.
I don't fall into that rim sleep.
>> It's a stress sleep. You can almost
still hear what's going on, but you're
not, you know, it's not a restful sleep.
It was like Jesus was in a rim sleep. He
was in a deep sleep. He wasn't worried
about
>> napping. He was
>> That's the example.
>> Wow. REM.
>> Yeah. You can call it REM instead of
pillow.
>> The
>> Listen y'all. I mean, in a REM, when
you're in REM stage of rest,
y'all about to make me write another
book.
when you're in a REM state of rest that
you're just such in a deep sleep that
>> you know it the storms can't wake you
>> and it's almost like wow is that the
devil's trying to keep us you know awake
trying to keep us restless
>> and Jesus is trying to give us that rim
sleep
>> where it's just like man I was like I
was out
>> and And he wants us to be out and he
wants to live in us and we're out.
>> We're out.
>> Which is
>> like, let me just
>> Yeah. I mean, when the when the when
death is a deep sleep,
>> that's what death is.
>> That's what it is.
>> Death is a deep sleep.
>> So when you're sleeping,
>> when you're resting, when you're in that
deep state of rest, and the devil's
like, "Wake up. Wake up.
This is going to happen." He's just
like,
Nah, I'm good. I'm sleeping.
>> The disciples like, "Jesus, wake up."
>> And you know when Jesus wakes up, it's
an object lesson. He's like,
>> "Wait, that's what you worried.
>> Storm, can you stop?" And the storm
stops.
>> So, I can go back to sleep.
>> Can I go back to sleep now?
>> Transfer to everything around him.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> Wow. Okay.
>> Okay. Wow. I never saw that before.
>> Say you want to say that again,
Michaela, because I don't know.
>> He swear he was able to sleep through
the middle of the storm
>> transferred to the chaos going around
him on around him and his disciples.
>> Amen. Amen. I was going to say even
deeper than REM sleep is when you're
when you have to have surgery and you're
under anesthesia. Nothing can you don't
know nothing can wake you up until
>> the anesthesia has you know
>> worn off or at a lower point
>> and you don't know what's happening. So
like when you're in that deep of a sleep
it's like God is just working all kinds
of miracles and you have nothing to do
with it and he's working out your whole
situation. He's fighting the battle for
you.
>> He's responding for you in the way that
needs to be. like you don't know what's
going on. You just wake up and it's
like, "Oh, I just blinked my eye and
now."
>> Yeah.
>> That's a powerful thought to to have God
respond for you. To have God
>> You're out of it.
>> Yeah. I'm Yeah. Let God respond to that.
>> You're preparing for surgery.
>> And he does the spiritual surgery on
your on your heart, in your situation.
Anyways, we can go on and on about this.
Yeah, we want to be resting.
We want to be rest.
>> So I think, you know, I think going back
to that whole martial arts
>> idea of
resisting
retaliation, resisting giving into the
storm, holding on to your peace,
that battle. And I think we talked about
this like kind of last week about, you
know,
the war being a war to maintain your
peace,
>> right? Being a battle to
stay calm.
>> Yes.
>> And to stay rested
in Christ.
>> Amen.
>> Um, and a lot of us don't even look at
the battle that way, right? We're just
>> I think for a lot of a lot of
Christians,
>> you know, a martial artist spends days
day in and day out practicing the art
of, okay, if this were to happen, how do
I respond? How do I And they're
practicing. And you know, how much more
should we as Christians
>> be practicing?
>> Be practicing. How am I going to respond
when somebody comes at me sideways?
>> Especially your husband or your wife or
your children,
>> a co-orker, a family member.
>> And listen, when when when we practice
the martial arts, like we would spend
just every minute of the day imagining
fight scenarios where we come out in in
victory. We'd be like, you know what? I
think I could actually beat 15 guys if
they came to fight for to fight us. I
think I I think I could take them.
>> Wow.
>> And then 15 would just be like that's ah
you know that's a small number
>> you know and you would just kind of your
mind would be constantly in that how
would I fight? How would I fight? How
could I beat that? How could I beat that
person? If I fought that person could I
beat that? What would I if I was in a
situation where this happened? How would
I respond? And the martial artist mind
is always thinking, how would I get the
victory? How would I get the victory?
>> Do we do that? Do we have that same
passion for the Christian art of war
>> that the martial artist has for his
style of fighting?
>> They do all of that.
>> They want to be prepared just in case,
but they don't want to have to do that.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah.
that. So they're learning
>> at the same time that they're training
how to defeat.
>> They're also fighting the battle of
getting victory.
>> So they don't have to Yeah. They don't
have to respond. It doesn't have to be a
fight. Somebody might be coming at them
or might be saying something to them.
They don't have to respond. So it's not
going to escalate to an actual physical
fight.
>> And and here's the reason why.
>> Or even a fight with words.
>> Yeah.
The martial artist who knows how good he
is will take a he he'll take a hit. You
know what?
>> All right. You
>> I could hurt you.
>> You just you just slap me in the face.
All right. Let Let me Let me walk away
because if I don't walk away, you you
will be on the ground laying out for
several hours when I'm done with you.
And I'm not going to do that. you.
There's this sense of
>> I'm gonna extend mercy to
>> and here's the thing. Jesus on the
cross, it is exactly what he was
exercising
>> because
>> he could have
>> the devil was trying to tempt him.
>> He could have come down
>> to come down
>> and I mean with the blink of an eye or
with a thought
>> he could have wiped out all of his
enemies.
>> And so understand
how
He had to hold.
Listen,
>> and I preached this a few weeks, a few
months ago,
>> that for us,
>> we can think evil of someone. We can
think, you know, I wish you were and but
our thoughts don't have power. We have
to act it out.
>> Yeah.
>> To bring it to pass.
>> Not so with God.
God's word has creative power in it and
he does not need to just speak the word.
All he needs to do is think the thing
>> and it is so. Right. So Jesus
had to not even by thought
>> think violence
>> towards his enemies
>> because it would have come
>> because it would have happened if he
thought it.
And and what we do is we don't just
think violence. Sometimes we do the
violence. And if it's not physical
violence, we do with our words verbal
violence.
>> And we're really just hurting ourselves.
>> Yeah.
>> Yep.
>> Like yes, if the person
>> we're doing violence to others, but
we're also doing violence to ourselves.
>> It hurts their feelings as well, but
we're really hurting ourselves.
>> Yeah.
So we think about that that
>> and we think we're doing something.
Yeah. Oh, I told her.
>> I told him.
>> Ain't nobody get on me. What?
>> Okay.
>> Jesus
Jesus the way that he held his peace
even in thought.
>> That's where the battle of peace is
fought. It's in the thoughts.
>> So how do I learn to hold my peace?
Not
I hate you inside, but I'll smile at
you.
>> Happy Sabbath, you know. Good.
>> I I hate you. I'm mad at you inside. I
hate you inside, but you know, if I had
the opportunity, I'd beat you down, but
I'm not strong enough or I don't have
the opportunity, so I'm not going to do
that. Right?
>> That's not real victory.
>> Real victory is holding your peace,
>> right? Mhm.
>> mentally
>> so that you cannot be moved by the
storms around you. That's the real
battle.
>> And that's what Jesus that's what Jesus
expressed or demonstrated on the cross.
He held this peace. And let me go back
to that. The God of peace shall bruise
Satan under your feet shortly.
That is what Jesus did. Jesus defeated
the devil at Calvary through
>> peace.
>> Yes,
>> through peace.
>> You did preach that. That was powerful,
too. It's powerful right now. Say again.
To win through peace. To get victory
through peace.
>> Strength through peace.
>> Strength through peace. That's another
shirt.
>> Start making my own shirts. That that is
so powerful.
>> Strength through peace.
>> Yeah.
>> So, all right.
>> Um,
anything you guys want to add?
Um, I mean, I don't know. We we've read
through the whole the whole uh section
of peace. Um I think we can build on it
more or we can we got another section
coming up and I don't know how much time
we have but we may just wait.
>> I think we should wait because we don't
want to like Yeah.
>> So the next section and all of you
should have you know the the the PDF but
our next spirit is patience.
>> Our next our next fruit of the spirit.
Yeah.
>> Yep. Is patience. And I I I please guys,
don't rush through what this what don't
rush through any of it. But today was
just so
powerful.
>> Like
>> I got one I got one more thing to say.
>> Yes, please. I want you all to have a
closing remark, please.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. The thing about um
>> Okay. Okay. Yeah. The thing about
peace, especially when you hold your
tongue and you let whatever is happening
just happen and then you're able to see
how the Holy Spirit works in the
situation and for yourself. It's truly a
beautiful thing when people see you hold
your peace, especially when they know
that they're being ridiculous.
>> And
that's that you it's you could actually
see it in their eyes most times
and you could see the Holy Spirit
ministering to them.
>> And then you recognize that that it's
addicting for me. It's addicting to see
when I hold my tongue and just let it
go.
>> To see how beautiful it works when you
just allow the Holy Spirit to work just
by holding a piece.
>> Amen.
>> He just he just he just takes care of
it.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. And he wants that
for all of us. Um, he wants us to
experience having that victory by
holding our peace. And guys, I would be
out, well, maybe not completely out of a
job, but I would be out of the the
marriage part of a job working with
couples if we could just learn how to
how to have victory through peace. Hold
our peace.
>> Hold our peace. Um,
>> I got Oh.
>> Oh, go ahead. And I wanted to see if if
Melinda or Michaela had some closing
remarks on peace.
>> Yeah. And I I just have one more
thought. I was just thinking of this as
uh we're getting ready to close, but I
want you to think about um
the people that put Jesus to death, that
beat him, that spat upon him,
>> that bore false witness against him,
right? All of these things that were
done, these wrathful, angry things that
were done to him.
And then three days later,
they hear that he's alive.
>> Oh my god.
>> Now, I'm going to I'm going to ask my
guests. Can we pull our pull our guests
up for a second? So, I'm gonna ask you
guys,
what do you think
would have been running through their
minds as they're like, "Wait,
he's alive."
>> Now, you know, right, if we're living in
if we're in in living in today's day and
with all the movies, you just be like,
>> "The movies, the movies.
>> Is he gonna appear by my bedside while
I'm sleeping in the middle of the
night?" Like,
>> who knows?
>> I mean, just imagine the fears
>> that are running through their mind when
they're like,
>> "He's alive.
>> He's coming to get me. He is I I know
it. I know it. If he's alive,
>> I'm dead."
>> Because that's the carnal
>> The Bible say
there's no peace for the wicked, right?
>> If somebody gets into power, they're
going to they're going to try
>> they're going to try to get vengeance.
>> Vengeance, mercy. We're seeing a lot of
that today
>> and
>> in America.
>> Yes. But he didn't do that.
>> You see what I'm saying?
>> He maintained his peace when in their
minds they were probably self- condemned
just thinking.
>> I mean, they may have never rested a day
in their life
>> again. Yeah.
>> Like if he's alive, I'm just waiting for
the day. I'm gonna be sleeping at night
and wake up and he's standing right
there.
>> No.
>> We're like, "Oh, so you wonder why?" But
that's not who Jesus is.
>> That's not who he was. That's not who he
is.
>> And that's not who we should be.
>> And if it was us,
>> even if we're done done wrongly.
>> Yeah. If it was us,
>> Yeah. we'd be like, "All right, 12 a.m.
Nah, I'mma make it 100 a.m. in the
morning when he's in REM sleep.
need to be in sleep at that time.
>> Oh, wow. That's not
>> That was all I had to add.
>> Yeah, that's not who we should. But do
you guys have um M&M's?
Do you have any closing remarks?
If not, we're gonna we're definitely
going to follow up with it next week.
But if you have anything you can share
now before we say with prayer,
>> I did have one thing. Uh I guess it kind
of goes back to the title of the
chapter.
>> Um
something the teens were studying
recently that I found very very
impactful. I think Melinda mentioned we
started to look at the 23rd Psalm. We
didn't get very far,
>> but
>> the 23rd Psalm I think of it as like
probably the most one of the most
peaceful parts of the Bible.
>> Like green pastures, still waters, not
fearing
>> um dwelling in the house of the Lord all
the days of my life. It can't get more
peaceful than that.
>> But
>> yeah,
>> we're kind of looking at it through the
lens of a study of
how does this relate to me?
>> And the 23rd Psalm honestly often feels
really distant like
>> this is heaven or something.
>> But it has a whole another dimension to
it. I realized like
so this was written by David
and it's kind of actually a little bit
of a summary of his life and David's
life we looked at it is nothing
>> it's not anything near peaceful
>> right nothing
>> so it starts the Lord is my shepherd
right
>> we looked at it
beginning of David's life he was a
shepherd he was alone a lot of the
times.
>> He was his father, his brothers kind of
overlooked him and he was feeling very
alone.
>> But here he says he has sense of
belonging because he says the Lord is my
shepherd.
>> And then later it goes on to um how
walking through the valley the shadow of
death. David fought battle in a valley
>> and then
>> Oh wow. Um, wow.
>> So,
>> it's like, and then anointing my head
with oil, kingship, all of it. It's just
like, and then the very end, I will
dwell in the house of the Lord all the
days of my life. David wanted to build
God, build God's temple, right? But he
couldn't because
he was a man of war. He had blood on his
hands. So, David's life was full of war.
But he wrote the psalm
of his life through a lens of peace
>> and finding having victory
um of his shepherd days through his um
becoming a soldier days to becoming king
days to the end of his life.
All these battles he fought, he viewed
through a lens of peace, trusting,
trusting in God, trusting in his
shepherd, and having belonging. So, I
felt like that was pretty incredible
personally.
>> Amen.
>> Yeah. Wow.
>> Yeah. There was one last thing I also
wanted to add and I don't know who said
that. I think it might have been pastor
or Kashif, but I just wanted to go off
that. Sometimes the storm isn't in our
surroundings. Sometimes it's within
ourselves.
>> A lot of the times it's within
>> And when the storm inside us is raging,
we need to have a
>> a a deeper place to go to. And I'm not
talking about like the subconscious. I'm
talking about God's spirit and his
abiding within us. We need to be able to
lean back and go back on that and say,
"Okay, Jesus, I believe you're with me
and I believe you're with me in this
valley of the shadow of death like
Michaela was talking about." And I think
that will give us peace like like pastor
said, when we have the comforter around
us, even the storm inside our own head,
the storm can't wake us up.
>> Amen.
>> Yes.
>> Absolutely beautiful. Thank you guys for
sharing that. Thank you all for your
contribution to today's study and um I
pray that our viewing audience will even
go back and watch and just take it a
little bit slower. Don't don't
>> just just take it all to into heart to
to heart and to study and pray and and
just you know ask God how you can have
this type of peace.
>> Yeah. Y
>> and your daily walk. Y
>> so
thank you guys for for viewing and thank
you to our guest our panelists always so
great to have you here and we are going
to continue our discussion on peace next
week. So um do you want to share
anything about your sermon?
>> Yeah uh my sermon uh will be I just will
let you know not be what you think. I'm
just going to leave it right there.
never is what you guys think.
>> Make sure you tune in. Make sure you let
people know, hey, sermon's coming up.
>> Stay tuned.
>> It's send out the the link again.
Subscribe to the Living Mana YouTube
channel if you have not done so yet.
>> Uh and uh let people know sermon's
coming up. Please tune in. Um watch it.
May God uh use it to impact your life
and to draw you closer to Jesus.
>> Amen. Amen. And so yes, invite friends
and family uh to church, continue to
worship with us, and we're just going to
close in prayer.
>> All right, want to pray?
>> Okay. Heavenly Father, thank you so much
for this study on peace uh today. It was
so many powerful nuggets, Lord, that we
need to take to heart and to apply to
our daily lives. Lord, transform us,
change us, help us to experience this
type of peace, your peace in Jesus name.
Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Continue to to worship with us today.
We'll see you in the divine worship
service.
We're here in the beautiful golden state
of California in the city of San
Francisco where we find one of the most
beautiful and surely the most
photographed bridge in all the world,
the Golden Gate Bridge. Let's go check
it out.
The Golden Gate Bridge is the iconic
symbol of San Francisco. When it opened
in 1937, it was the longest suspension
bridge in all the world, connecting its
main city to its upper peninsula.
Considered as one of the great wonders
of the modern world by the American
Society of Civil Engineers.
Aesthetically beautiful and structurally
sound, it is San Francisco's pride and
joy.
The Golden Gate Bridge is also known as
a dark and dreary dead-end road for so
many people. It is the second most used
suicide bridge in the world. claiming
the lives of over 1500 people in death
throughout the years. In fact, it's on
this very road that one of my beloved
friends tried to take her life in death.
>> She grew up in a very loving environment
surrounded by life. But on the inside,
she was in a cage of emptiness and
spiritual death. She had made many
mistakes in the realm of her
relationships. And because of her
brokenness, she was discarded like
trash. The devil whispered lies into her
ears, saying that God doesn't love you.
You're dirty. You're unworthy. You might
as well end it all right now here. And
so she drove to this bridge intending to
jump off to take her life. She was at
the end of her road and she felt like
there was no way out.
>> Where is the love?
Where is the guide?
Does it exist?
>> The God of grace came to her rescue.
Love came down to bring restoration. On
her way to the bridge, she received a
phone call from a loved one that assured
her that her life is still worth
something. That no matter what happened
in her past, she is still deeply loved.
The good Lord was giving her a second
chance in infinite love and mercy.
In that defining moment, she realized
that Christ was the golden gate,
providing a way of escape from her
depression and despair. She realized
that his death on the cross, not hers on
this bridge, was the solution to her
sorrows. And so she accepted his way of
escape and entered into the golden gate
of his grace.
So instead of jumping off this bridge,
she crossed over. And as she crossed
through this literal bridge, in reality,
spiritually, she was crossing over from
death into life, from sorrow into
salvation, from fear into freedom. She
made it through by the bridge of his
love. And today, she has hope and she
has peace.
>> You see, this story of redemption
illustrates the reality that no matter
how far we have fallen, love came down
to bring restoration. I want you to know
that there is a loving God that came all
the way down from heaven to earth to
meet us in our misery. He came to a
world that was cut off by sin. A world
that was committing spiritual suicide
and determined disobedience. A world
separated from the heavenly peninsula by
a bay of brokenness. And God so loved
this world that he came to build a
bridge. A bridge that all may enter
freely without a toe and without a
price. A bridge for all of humanity to
pass from death into life. It is a
bridge made of one cross and three
nails. For one cross plus three nails
equals forgiveness for all who will
receive it.
Now outwardly this bridge may look weak,
but this wooden bridge is more
structurally sound than the steel
suspension bridge we stood upon earlier
today. For on that wooden cross,
suspended in midair, hung one who held
the weight of the world in his hands.
One who is strong enough to endure all
the massive misery and the burden of
brokenness that sin had brought upon the
human race. And that man's name is
Jesus. He is one that died so that we
might live. Please don't let his death
be in vain. Stay on the bridge. The
devil may be telling you today that
because of the sins of your past that
there's no hope for you and that you've
gone too far. But friends, please stay
on the bridge. Today you might find
yourself drowning in a sea of sorrow due
to a terrible accident, the loss of a
loved one, a financial hardship, a
deadly diagnosis, maybe the betrayal of
a friend, the unfaithfulness of a
spouse, the backstabbing of a brother,
the rejection of a child, or the
indifference of the church. But my
friends, I plead with you. Don't jump
off the bridge. There is an answer to
your problem and a solution to your
sorrows.
As Jesus hung up on the cross, he was
tempted to come down, tempted to jump
off of the bridge. But Jesus stayed on
the bridge for you. It is his death, not
yours, that is the way of escape. And
because he stayed on the wooden bridge
for you, today I encourage you to stay
on the heavenly bridge with him.
And if you do, soon you will experience
the joy of entering into the heavenly
golden gate to experience life forever
more. And by God's grace, I'll see you
on the other side.
Your love came down.
>> Love came down.
>> Your love came down
came
down for me.
>> Love came down.
>> Love
came
down.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Hey, hey, hey.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Welcome back Living Mana Church family.
We are so happy that you have stayed
with us. Some of you are just joining us
for the first time today, but we are so
happy that you have some of you have
continued to worship with us. And for
for those who have just joined us for
the first time today, want to say a
special welcome to you. Please, if
you're just joining us just now, please
put in the chat where you are viewing
from. We want to say uh welcome to you
and to greet you. And if this is your
first time here at Living Mana Church,
please put a one in the chat and where
you're viewing from. We love to see our
viewing audience, the location of our
viewing audience from all around the
world. I know I've been saying this for
three and a half years that it excites
us. It makes us happy, but it truly does
because it just lets us know every week
that we truly are an international
church. I know this past Monday when Dr.
White um and I were doing uh Mental
Health Monday, we had uh somebody from
um not Croatia, but it's somewhere right
near Croatia and I'm forgetting. Um, oh
my goodness, I told myself I was going
to remember and I just forgot. But
however, we had it was a first timer
watching uh Mental Health Monday. Um,
and they were right near Croatia, a
neighboring country. So, and we had Oh,
and I know Mental Health Monday, we had
somebody from Thailand. Um, and we had
uh two from Australia. So, we are just
truly an international church and we are
so thankful to have all of you here. Um,
and you tune in each and every week, not
just on Sabbath, but during our week
programs as well. So, just to remind you
and let some of you know the ones, those
of you putting a one in the chat for the
very first time. Again, we are an
international church and we're not just
here on Sabbath, but we are here all
throughout the week. We have mental
health programmings on Monday. We have
true health Tuesday physical health
programming. We have two prayer services
on Wednesday. We have the power line and
power Wednesday all on Wednesday. So,
two prayer services there. And then we
have programming for young adults on
Thursdays. And so, and that's done by
our young adult pastor, uh, Pastor Lwami
Richardson. And so, we are here all
throughout the week. And so we want you
uh to learn more about our church and to
get connected and to and to find um just
your space here at Living Mana Church.
And a way that you can stay connected
here to Living Mana is you can get text
messages. If you are in North America,
you can get text messages and you can
sign up to get that. And so the way that
you do that is just text LMOC to
855207-4107
and all of those programs that I was
telling you about. You will get a
reminder if you're here in North
America, you will get a reminder on your
cell phone that Living Man is about to
go live. And so 20 minutes before Mental
Health Monday goes live, you will get
that reminder. 20 minutes before any of
our programming goes live, you will get
that reminder because we all know that
we're very busy and we may want to uh
see Mental Health Monday, like on
Sabbath, you're like, "Huh, that sounds
like a good program. I'm going to do
that on Monday." But then life is just
lifeing and things just happen. And so
you may forget, even I sometimes forget,
not about mental health Mondays because
I'm one of the hosts, but about other
things. and then it will pop up uh the
reminder will pop up on my phone and
I'll be like, "Oh yeah, I'm going to do
that." So, or I want to I want to see
that. I want to watch that. And so, I
would don't want you to miss any of that
programming just because you forgot. And
that's you can just stay connected if
you sign up. And we also send out other
important information as well. Now, this
text LOC, this 855 number to get the
text only works if you're in North
America. If you are anywhere else uh in
the world in other countries, you will
need to sign up for Mighty Networks. And
you're going to see the link in the chat
now. So you can sign up for Mighty
Networks. And Mighty Networks is our
virtual church home. That's what it is,
our virtual church home. That is where
we have small groups. You get to learn
all about our small groups. You see can
see the leaders. You can see all the
information about the small groups to
see if you want to join the small group.
You get to meet um other people who are
watching uh living mana church viewing
audience and members. You get to meet so
many different people from all around
the world right there on mighty network
and you get to it's our it's where we
are able to form community and to make
friends as well here at Living Mana
Church. So again, the link is in the
chat and you can uh just click the link
and so that you can download Mighty
Network or join it if you have not. Um
there's so many amazing things there and
again it's our virtual church home. So
you're not going to want to not sign up.
So even if you are in America, you still
want to sign up for Mighty Networks, but
if you're outside of America, that's how
you're going to get reminders is through
uh Mighty Network. So, we're just so
thankful to be able to have that and for
you to be able to join that as well.
Just a reminder that we do have
children's programming. We have LOC kids
and if you would like to get your child
involved in LMOC Kids, the way that
you're able to do that is to text kids
to that 855 number. Also, you can send
an email to LMOC Kids at Livingmana.urch
church and the leadership of LMC Kids
will get back with you. As you can see
there on the screen, LMOC Kids um is at
11:30 Central time and they go for about
90 minutes on Sabbath morning. So again,
if you want to get your child involved,
that is the information there and they
are learning some of the deep things of
God's uh in that's in God's word at a
child's level. And so, uh, they are
having a lot of fun doing so. So,
definitely get your, um, your child, um,
or, um, your nieces or nephews and hey,
maybe even your grandchildren involved
in LMLC kids. They will love it. All
right. Um, just want to see here that
pastor, I just want to let you know that
pastor Myers has virtual church office
hours. If you need to talk to him and
you'd like to set up a meeting, you can
email put that email that you see on the
screen, but that's patrice
livingmana.live
and you will be able to set up uh a
meeting with pastor meers. You're going
to be able to use that same email if you
are wanting to become a member of Living
Mana Church. And there's three different
ways that you can become a member. If
you are a member of another 7th Day
Adventist church, but you want to become
a member of LivingMana Church, you can
just use that email patrice livinga.live
and uh she will take it from there and u
be able to help you to be able to
transfer your membership.
If um you are are wanting to become a
member through profession of faith uh
because you don't feel like you need to
be baptized but you do want to join the
7th day Adventist church you can do that
um by profession of faith and so you
just need to use that same email uh that
you see there on your screen and if you
want to become get baptized to become a
member you can do that as well and
pastor meers will baptize you. So that
email is used for those three different
ways to become a member here at Living
Mana Church. Also want to let you guys
know about some volunteer opportunities
here at Living Mana Church. Um if you're
ready to serve, we got open doors and
open roles. Um these are some of the
open roles we have. head or you need to
head to the service opportunity section
on Mighty Networks to see where your
gifts can make a difference right now.
Uh we're especially looking for
greeters, admins, communications,
production team. Whether you love
welcoming people, organizing behind the
scenes, crafting messages, or working
with tech, we've got a spot for you.
Let's build together. Let's serve
together. So those are the needed
volunteer positions. Um and you would um
find that space on mighty networks and
so uh you can get involved by going
there. Um as was uh previously stated.
Also want to let you know about a small
group. Uh STAR.
STAR is a support group um is here to
walk with you through the journey of
addiction recovery. Whether you're just
beginning or continuing the path toward
healing, you're not alone. This is a
safe, judgment-free space to share,
grow, and rebuild one step at a time.
Text star to 855207-4107
or email star at living.urch.
Meetings are open to anyone seeking
support, encouragement, and real
connection. come as you are. Um, hope
lives here. So, if you are interested in
that, please send a text, send an email
so that you can get involved.
Also want to let you know about glow
groups. Glow groups are small digital
gatherings where we dive deep into
pastor's sermons and the word of God
together. These groups are designed for
real connection, thoughtful study, and
joyful fellowship. Members also um
started to use photo theology chat GPT
to play Bible games and explore
scripture in fresh um interactive ways.
If you're interested in joining or
starting one of these housefires, email
groups at living.urch.
Let's grow, glow, and get deeper
together. So, if you're interested in
that, please send an email so you can
get involved as well. Want to just say
thank you to everyone for their um love
and support and prayers and financial
giving. It is a blessing uh because
you're letting God use you to spread the
word and to support this church and
ministry. And if you would like to
continue to give or start giving, you
can do that virtually by going to
adventistgiving.org.
There you will put in living manaurch
and you will see a virtual tithe
envelope. And there you can see where
you will be able to put your tithe, your
uh local church offering. you will be
able to give to the benevolence fund
which helps um us to be able to support
those who are in need and come to come
to the church for support. There are so
many different categories on that tithe
envelope. Um, and you will be able to
give to whatever your heart uh desires.
And when you give your tithe, that does
go to the um Northeastern Conference,
which Living Mana Church is a part of
that conference. And that what when you
give to the local church budget, that's
what stays with Living Mana Church to
support all the things that we're doing
here. helps us to um support others,
stay up todate with all of the technical
things with the studio and cameras and
all of those types of things, lighting,
anything that goes into an online
production that comes from you giving to
the local uh church budget. So, um that
is where um those funds come from, from
the local church budget. Now, if you're
not wanting to give online, you are able
to still mail in a check, and that is
the address where you can do that. Just
please send a little note to let us know
what is for tithe, what's for offering,
or other things that you would like to
support and give to to Living Mana
Church. And again, we just want to say
thank you for your faithfulness and
following um God uh just whatever he's
putting on your heart to continue to
support Living Mana Church through your
prayers, through your attendance,
through sharing um that we are here and
talking about what Living Mana Church is
doing, sharing the sermon, sharing our
small groups and all of our different
programming throughout the week and also
financially giving to Living Manage
Church. That is how we are able to
continue uh to stay going into all of
the world. But the most important thing
is your prayers and we just thank you so
much for that uh because that has kept
us these three and a half years. It's
kept us going and we just ask that you
continue to pray for this church.
Speaking of prayer, we want to pray
right now a prayer of thanksgiving. Just
thanking God for what he has done uh for
Living Mana Church. So, if you could
please just bow your heads with me as we
pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I want to thank
you for this Sabbath day. I want to
thank you for the blessings that the
Sabbath brings. Lord, I want to thank
you for the Sabbath school that we had
uh this morning and just just
understanding what true peace looks like
and why you want to give us peace. Lord,
it's such a blessing. And so, Lord, I
just I just praise you. I just praise
you for that fruit of the spirit, that
gift that you have given to us. Lord, I
want to thank you for our viewing
audience, those who are watching now,
those who will watch later. Lord, you
know their specific prayer request. You
know what they're going through. Lord, I
pray that you will answer their prayers.
Let them know that you are with them.
Help them to feel your presence in their
life. Lord, I pray for Pastor Meyers. I
pray that the Holy Spirit will just uh
bless him with the message that you have
given to him. That he will deliver that
message to all of us and that it will
change our hearts and our lives forever.
Lord, we just thank you again for this
Sabbath day in Jesus precious name.
Amen.
Dawn broke on the darkest day in
history.
That's where its story began.
The cross,
a weapon
so painful and cruel that even the sight
of it would strike fear into one's own
heart.
So, how is it that this perfect symbol
of death could become the way
to new life?
How one broken body
could heal all brokenness.
Suspended between heaven and earth.
Stripped naked for all to see.
Hanging from an ancient symbol of fear,
only to become the eternal symbol of
hope.
It was never going to be an easy path.
Pain and suffering must still be
endured.
But as we each take up our own cross,
God uses the perfect symbol of our
frailty as the greatest sign of his
strength
and his power to turn what was meant for
evil into the greatest good the world
has ever seen.
And show the greatest love the world
will ever know.
The cross
for you,
for me,
forever.
I just can't give up now.
>> I've come too far from where I started
from.
Nobody told me
the road would be easy. And I don't
believe
he's brought me this far to lead me.
>> Never said there wouldn't be trials.
Never said I would fall.
Never said that everything
would go the way I wanted to go.
But when my back was against the wall
and I feel hope is gone,
I'll just lift my head up to the sky.
and say, "Help me to be strong."
Oh,
I just can't give up now.
Come too far from where I started
from.
Nobody told me
the road would be
I don't believe he's brought me this far
to leave me.
>> I know you didn't leave me
out here to leave me lonely.
Even when I can't see clearly,
I know that you are with me. So I can't.
I just can't give up now.
Come too far from where I started
from.
Nobody told me
the road would be
I don't believe he brought me this far
to leave me. Just sing that over your
life today.
>> Oh, I don't believe he's brought me this
far to leave me. moving forward, Lord.
Oh, I don't believe he's brought me this
far to leave me.
I don't believe he's brought me this far
to leave me. Oh
yeah. I don't believe he's brought me
this far to leave me.
I don't believe
he's brought me this far to leave me.
I don't believe he's brought me this far
to leave me.
No, I don't believe he's brought me this
far to leave me.
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
Greetings, saints of the most high God.
Welcome, Living Man of Family. So good
to see everyone here today. I'm brother
Terry. This is my lovely bride, Amra. We
are so thankful to God for allowing us
to be able to serve in this capacity.
Listen, it never gets old, saints. And
uh we're continuing to uh press on and
fight the good fight of faith. See you
all in the chat. Hey everybody. Good
seeing y'all. Everybody got a chance to
come out last night communion service.
That was just beautiful. Enjoyed y'all.
>> And uh really really thank God for the
work that he's doing in and through the
body of Christ. Just giving God praise
for everybody today. Again, I also want
to thank our beautiful tech team working
behind the scenes making it all happen.
Everybody back there, we are indeed
working together as a family. Thank
y'all for everything you'll do. I know
sometime we do stuff that just drive
y'all crazy, right? But, uh, we're
getting it together. So, uh, thank you
so much. Uh, did want to do some shout
outs, but I won't today because let me
just say, hey everybody, okay, love
y'all. Love the prayer warriors in the
chat. Love the work y'all are doing.
Thank you so much. You know what? Let me
say this.
Everything today you've heard, whether
it be the Sabbath school discussion on
peace, whether it be Taj's video on that
bridge, we're here in sunny California
and the Golden Gate Bridge. He talked
about how that can be uh it's the most,
you know, photographed bridge in the
world. Uh but for a lot of people, it's
just the end of the road because they
don't see it for the blessing that it
is. want to talk about that a little
bit. But also that that that song we
just heard from Mary Mary uh I don't
believe he's brought me this far to
leave me. If you're watching today we
pray that God is speaking to your heart
right where you are right in your
circumstances right in your situation.
Um storms come saints they do. uh why
Solomon said whether you are one who
sacrifices or you don't sacrifice
whatever the case there's one event to
everyone but the difference for us is we
have a living hope we have the Lord
Jesus Christ and so I just want to reach
out to you we want to reach out to you
the entire living mana family may God
speak in and through us to give you hope
today as a matter of fact you may not
have seen this or heard this in the chat
but Sister Wendy Allen put something in
the chat this morning she says Please
ask for and receive forgiveness from him
who loves us so much. Please don't
let his love for you be in vain. Come to
him for forgiveness. Accept his
forgiveness. Accept his forgiveness.
Thank you for putting that in the chat
today, Sister Wendy, because you're
helping to preach the gospel by this
encouraging word that you put right
there in the chat today. And she put
that in there as Taj's video was going
because there was a song played in the
background. I know some of y'all heard
that song was that song was moving. It
said love came down
>> and love did come down. But you know
what? A lot of times we look for relief.
We look for satisfaction. We look for
hope and everything else but the one
place we can find it. And thank God for
his patience putting up with us while we
run everywhere. I ran all the way around
the world and back tried some of
everything. Nothing has satisfy my soul.
And saints, I'm going to tell you,
nothing can fill that Jesus-shaped void
in your heart but Jesus. And so, want to
encourage you today, seek him and find
him. Uh and speaking of storms, our our
beloved uh country of Jamaica, we know
that it just faced a a major storm and
um there's a lot of devastation and
there and there is a lot of need there.
And with our government cutting off um
uh a lot of support, you know, the
church, it's time for the church to step
up and be the people of God. You know,
there is one in 10 people in Jamaica are
Seventh Day Adventist. And we're not
just showing the love of God to
Adventists, but particularly to the
household of faith. We do uh uh the
pride minister there and leaders, key
leaders there are Adventists. And so we
do want to share the love of God with
our people there and make sure we do
that. And so we want to talk to you
today about uh reaching out uh uh and
perhaps making a a donation through
Adventist Relief. uh if you can you can
donate online digitally or if not I
believe we're putting up the address for
you here in the lower section there at
adr.org or that's at ADRA. And if you
can't for some reason donate digitally,
there's also an address that you can
maybe mail a check to Adventist Relief
and you can send your check there. We'll
get that address. It will be either in
the chat or or we'll put it up in the
lower region there in the on the screen.
There's the address. Yes, it was just
up. And so we'll keep working with that
because we Silver Strings uh Michigan
20994.
It's it's it's uh uh 12501 Old Columbia
Pike, Silver Springs, Maryland uh 20904.
And and let me repeat that again so you
won't have any of my mistake in the way.
You'll have the correct address that's
right there on the screen. You can copy
it. Um uh or even when we play this
back, you can go back and get the
address, but we'll leave it there on the
screen for a little bit. Want to want to
send some love to Jamaica. Really,
really saints. We want to uh stand up
and be the hand of feet of Jesus. I want
to say something about Jamaica while I'm
on that topic. This morning on the
pre-ervice huddle, one of our prayer
warriors, one of our close and precious
sisters, you've heard me talk about her
many times, Sister Karen Johnson, she's
right there in the heart of the storm.
And she's right there with us praying on
fire and singing and declaring uh the
goodness of God and the works of God in
Jamaica
today, you know. And so sometimes saints
>> Karen's amazing. Karen is amazing and
and on fire and I love I love that
sister. She she was praying on Christ
the rock solid rock I stand. I heard it
in her song in her in her prayer. And so
we sang that for her today and we're
singing that for all of you beautiful
brothers and sisters in Jamaica. Those
of you have family and loved ones and
friends that are there. Uh let us show
some love to our beautiful people in
Jamaica. Jamaica, we love y'all. If
you're watching today, do know that we
are Mish Poha. We are family. And uh
hold on. Hold on. It's not over. May God
be glorified through the storms. Also, I
want to mention today that um the uh the
Atlantic Union Conference is having
their uh public relations and religious
liberty convocation in New York. And
three of the top meral candidates are
going to be speaking there. A matter of
fact, they're speaking five minutes
each. And then the keynote speaker today
will be our pastor, Pastor Ivan Meyer
going to be speaking there. And so
beautiful stuff.
>> But don't worry, there's a sermon today.
>> Yes, there's gonna be a sermon today. Of
course, u you know, God's doing what he
does. And so we want to uh keep that in
prayer what's going on there and some
beautiful stuff happening there. As a
matter of fact, Pastor going to get an
opportunity uh speaking of prayer,
they're going to be meeting uh a couple
of our living manner of prayer warriors
there. Uh, brother Kashif's gonna meet
them, be with them personally. Um, and
brother Kirk, and I believe Kirk's
bringing his cousin, too. So, thank God.
And also, check this out. Those of us
who have been praying for Dante's
brother Kevin, who a while back had a
had a had a stroke, as you recall. Kevin
is showing up for church today. And so,
we need to give God some praise.
>> And he looks so good.
>> Yeah. He looks He looks amazing. He's He
looks God is healing and restoring and
recovering. He'll do it. Somebody say,
"Amen." That's right. We're thinking of
you, Jamaica. We're praying for you,
Jamaica. And um also everything that's
going on, God is God is doing an
incredible work. And we see you all
there in the chat, everybody. Why? I
don't know why y'all want to make me
start this roll call because I know
>> we got all this stuff to do today. You
know what happens when we start with
roll call, right? I want to call
everybody.
>> We love everyone. Thank you so much for
your kind words and greetings in the
chat. Much love to you all.
>> Amen. Amen. Definitely. Definitely. And
so I did mention Wendy. Wendy, I love
what you typed in chat. My sister, God
bless you. And so you preach that gospel
today. So and listen, all of us, we all
can be digital evangelists. You can do
that. One thing you can hit that like
button. We're gonna we g Amen. Amen.
That's right. I see it. That's right.
Amen. For his health. I think that's
Leslie. Yes. And so, look, we can all be
digital evangelists. We're going to move
on to the praise report section. Ammer's
probably going to make some
announcements. We're going to go to
>> do some praise reports. Right. Before we
do the praise reports, can we take care
of a little bit of business? Can we
preach the gospel together for a minute?
>> Hit that like button. All right. Hit the
like button. I I see the likes right
now. All right. Hit the like button.
Subscribe. Make sure we get the the al
algorithm going for the channel. you
know, you YouTube will send out
notifications, but in and rather than
sitting back waiting on YouTube, we can
also, just like we're not gonna sit back
waiting on the government, we gonna do
what we got to do to help our brothers
and sisters in need. Another way we can
do that is share that link with
somebody.
>> Post it on your post it on your Facebook
page, post it on your social media
platform, post it somewhere, get it out
there. Even after this sh service is
over today, you can still do that and
still share. Get it out there and uh
let's share the matter. All right. Well,
>> amen.
>> Love y'all. Thank y'all. And uh just
praise God for you.
>> Amen.
>> All right.
>> Well, before I go into the praise
reports, just a few reminders.
If you have a prayer request or a praise
report that you would like to submit or
you would like to join us on the prayer
team or join a special ops team under
the prayer team umbrella, please send an
email to pray
living manana.urch.
If you would like to request a special
ops team for yourself or a loved one,
please send an email to spec ops at
livingmana.urch.
If you would like to join the women's
ministry on Mighty Networks, please send
an email to women
living manana.urch.
And if you would like to join the men's
ministry, their email has changed. It
used to be seven loaves, but it is now
much easier to remember. It is men at
living.urch.
>> Amen.
>> We also have a new small group led by
Sister Angela called the healing hour.
So, if you are living with chronic
illness, they are meeting for the first
time tomorrow, that's Sunday.
Um, and it's going to be the first
Sunday of every month to share, uplift,
and intercede together
and it will be on Zoom. For more
information on that, please go to Mighty
Networks and contact Angela to join and
come as you are and leave strengthened
and encouraged.
>> Amen.
>> Also, did you know that we have an LMC
Facebook page? If you would like to be
more into community, not just on living
uh
>> mighty
>> mighty networks,
>> but on social media, we have um look up
my living mana on Facebook. Um there is
postings of fresh inspiring content
daily from sermon highlights and prayer
prompts to behind the scenes ministry
moments. likes and shares are always
needed and engagement. So, please
comment on those posts so they can get
more traction and reach more people
>> and help build connection in the
community. All right, we are ready now
for our praise reports. The first one
coming from Jamie Abel. She has two.
Praise God for his grace and healing
power in my mom's health and daughter's
conversion.
And another praise report, Damon has
secured housing and a job servicing the
homeless. God has blessed him with an
ebike. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> That is huge blessing
from Jamie Grace asking for prayers for
Kibid Doula Adventist Mission in Africa.
There is unrest there in Tanzania due to
elections going on. There is a rumor of
a mob headed to G Kibby Doula now.
Please pray protection for all of our
missionaries there. Thank you. And the
update and praise report.
Update on Kibby Doula mission. The mob
was 1,000 strong and two miles away, but
turned to go in another direction.
Praise be to God. The missionaries are
safe for now. and I was interested in
learning a little bit more about this
mission. So I looked them up and they
happened to be on Instagram
and um they are doing a lot of work.
They have a school of evangelism. They
have um agricultural school that
includes huge production of avocados.
They even have a printing press where
they create their own tracks and
literature for evangelism and outreach.
So, praise God, they are doing huge
things in Tanzania.
>> Amen. One other thing, one other key
thing about Tanzania, and I know some of
you, you probably thinking, "Wait a
minute, Tanzania. Why does that sound
familiar?" Because our sister Kazia, who
sits on the Sabbath school panel with
us, is from Tanzania. Her parents are
members. She's members here with member
here with us. As a matter of fact, I was
connecting with Kazia earlier this
morning. And so when we do the youth
Sabbath, Kazia and I believe her niece
and her sister are going to be doing the
prayer segment. So we'll have a touch of
Tanzania right here with us. Oh, we also
saw another project uh in Tanzania where
the cows they were using, they're
experimenting with the cows mowing
between the avocado trees.
>> That's this mission.
>> Yes. Yeah. And so
>> it was really neat to see that
>> beautiful stuff. Tanzania, we love you.
Kazia, if you're watching, we love you
and thank you my sister. We'll continue
to pray for you and your family and for
Tanzania and thank you for all the work
you do here.
>> Yes. So, finally, we have now I was on
the phone with this sister several weeks
ago and there was just a bunch of stuff
happening all at once. Talk about a life
avalanche and God came through. So she
wants to share her testimony of um
praise today. So this one comes from
Ashley Owens and she has called this
praise report God's miraculous provision
and faithfulness.
On October 6th, my Dodge Grand Caravan
was totaled in an accident. Yet the
first miracle was that my children and I
were not in the vehicle at the time. The
second miracle was that the driver was
not injured even though the airbags
malfunctioned and never deployed. A
clear sign of divine protection.
During this time, my LOC family and
local SDA church surrounded me with love
and support. Sister Amar and Brother
Terry were always willing to take my
calls, pray with me, and help me make an
action plan. When I contacted my local
Florence First SDA church, I experienced
an outpouring of love as the members
truly became the hands and feet of
Jesus, helping me and my children with
rides to medical appointments and the
store. Then two days later, I received a
devastating letter from the social
security
stating that my disability benefits and
medical insurance would be discontinued.
This was terrifying because of my health
challenges, especially since the van had
a title loan of $9,863
and the driver at fault was not covered
by my insurance. It appeared the claim
would be rejected. The loan also stated
that if anyone other than me drove the
vehicle, the full balance could become
due immediately. At that moment, I felt
like I was standing at the Red Sea,
unable to see a way forward. Despite the
fear, I remembered my past answered
prayers and chose to trust that the same
God who delivered me before would do so
again. I focused on one step at a time,
filing my disability appeal, requesting
that my financial and medical benefits
remain in effect, and making an
appointment with my neurologist for
further testing. I also began the claim
process for the van. Then on October
20th, my local SDA pastor and his wife
offered to lend me their van large
enough for me and my five children. What
was meant to be a few days turned into a
week and then another miracle. They told
me I could keep the van until the last
week of November. This allows me to take
the kids to their specialist dental
appointments more than an hour and a
half away.
Then this Wednesday, I received a call
from the total loss claims agent. They
offered me $10,464
for the total van.
>> Come on, somebody.
>> That amount completely paid off the
title loan and even provided an extra
$620 check to help with other expenses.
On top of that, the monthly loan payment
of $356
and car insurance payment of $22
are now gone, freeing up funds for food
and family needs. Now, they listed
everything in the van as good on the
appraisal report. Definitely divine
intervention as my van was probably
going to be completely broken down in
six to nine months, useless in my
driveway with a payment. Regarding I
know
>> yes to Karen. What a mighty God we
serve.
>> Regarding my disability appeal after
meeting with my neurologist I was
officially diagnosed with generalized
epilepsy. Although the diagnosis is
daunting it also qualifies me for
disability benefits. Another answer to
prayer. Even in this I can see God's
hand preparing me. Back in April when I
was experiencing near daily seizure
activity, I had prayed for guidance and
watched Dr. Maria Jose Hmel on True
Health Tuesday. By the way, I did see
her in the chat saying, "Thank you for
the prayers. Her husband is feeling much
better."
Um, on True Health Tuesday, she
recommended the book Goodbye Lupus,
which inspired me to follow a diet and
lifestyle aligned with the SDA health
message. Since then, I've lost nearly 60
pounds and began began a vegetarian
ketogenic diet in September only to
discover later that the ketogenic diet
is often used therapeutically for
seizure management.
God was preparing my body in faith long
before I knew what was coming. Though I
still don't know the long-term car
solution, I have complete confidence
that God already has one prepared. I
just need to continue praying, trusting,
and waiting for his perfect timing. So,
if you are feeling discouraged or facing
your own giants, remember our God is the
living God, and nothing is too big for
him. He still parts the Red Seas, moves
mountains, and provides in ways we could
never imagine. And then she offered some
scripture references. Be behold, I am
the Lord, the God of all flesh. Is there
anything too hard for me? Jeremiah
32:27.
The Lord shall fight for you, and you
shall hold your peace. Exodus 14:14.
For he shall give his angels charge over
thee to keep thee in all thy ways.
Psalms 91:11.
Rest in the Lord, and wait patiently for
him. Psalms 37:7.
And my God shall supply all your need
according to his riches and glory by
Christ Jesus. Philippians 4:19.
Two more short ones because we can get
never get enough of the encouragement of
the word. Now unto him that is able to
do exceedingly abundantly above all that
we ask or think. Ephesians 3:20. And
finally, and we know that all things
work together for the good to them that
love God. Romans 8:28.
>> Well, come on. That is just amazing.
>> Look, Ashley,
>> what a journey Ashley has been on. Oh
my.
>> There's I'm sure you all know, saints,
there's more than one kind of storm,
right?
>> Yes.
>> That can hit your lives. Cuz some of
you, some of you, some of you are
spiritual stormtroopers. All of you are
because you're either in the middle of
one or coming out of one and heading
into another. We can remember at the
beginning of this thing, I was like,
"Oh, Lord Ashley." I mean, just one
thing after the next, boom, boom, boom.
But you hold on in the middle of your
storm. And she kept her head up high
through the whole thing.
>> She did. She did. And I'm telling you,
this this this this strong woman of God
and uh she held on and kept on praying
and y'all praying with her. And look,
you hold on. Your storm will preach in
the end, won't it?
>> It sure will.
>> I mean, come on, somebody. and her
praise report, you know, it's it's a
continue. It's gonna continue.
>> Yeah. And see, we don't we don't see it.
It's hard. I mean, look, Brother Terry,
the first one to start ripping his robe
and putting fat cloth and ashes on,
throwing ashes on. Look, I'll get out of
I get out of pocket, too, like any all
of us do. We we can't we don't always
hold our spiritual composure. But when
you look back and see what God is doing,
right, he cut off everything you was
depending on, brought you out of Egypt,
put you out there in the middle of the
wilderness. You don't have any
resources. Only thing you got to lean on
is him. And then here he comes.
>> Bread coming
>> from everywhere.
>> Comings
>> from everywhere. Somebody needs to hear
that this morning. This ain't just
Ashley's story. This somebody else
watching. Somebody you watching. You
thinking, "Oh man, the government
cutting off everything. They taking
jobs. They doing all this. God is
leading us to the kingdom." I saw
somebody put it in the chat this morning
that God will chase us to the place
where we have to take his matters. I
can't remember who put that in the chat,
but that was something else.
>> That's true.
>> Yes. Yes. So, thank you, God, for being
so good. And I And listen, we're going
to pray here. We're getting ready to
have some awesome prayer, but look, I'm
excited about the prayer time today as
we go to the altar because we get to
introduce somebody we know and love.
Look, we love everybody. We love each
other. But this is our special prayer
warette. You know, we've been praying
for Jamaica, but really our prayers are
covering all of the Caribbean because
we've seen pictures um from uh Haiti.
We've seen and heard reports from
Dominica. We've heard things about that
what's going on in Trinidad and Tobago
with all of the increase military
buildup there and some rumors about some
other stuff. Y'all know Jesus told
rumors of wars, right? Wars and rumors
of wars. But listen, here is our sister
from Triny on here.
>> Hi. This is Sister Ayana To.
>> Look, I was trying to set you up, but
they brought you on before I can finish.
>> That's okay. You can still set her up.
>> Yeah, I was trying to give her a big
setup. Y'all see her in the chat.
Listen, her and Sister Blessing be in
that chat praying for people. Her and
Sister Marcella Johnson. Jackie be in
the This is Sister Ayana who's always
praying for everybody, putting their
prayer requests in the chat. We gonna
have blessing on here shortly. But
Sister Ayana, we are so uh thankful to
God for you and your your your beautiful
spirit and your beautiful ministry and
your commitment. Some of the things
you're doing with some of the new
projects we got going on behind the
scene, they'll be out in a minute. But
thank you for coming, my beloved sister.
>> Hi everyone. Happy Sabbath. Thank you
for having me on. It's always a pleasure
to be in your presence. It's always a
pleasure to spend these little Sabbath
hours with you all. Um, I hope that you
all had a wonderful week and I'm glad to
be able to just come on and pray a
little bit for and with you guys. So, we
would have had some prayer requests that
I would have caught, but it's not too
late to put your prayer requests in the
chat.
>> Still put those prayer requests in the
chat. They will be collected and we pray
over them all week until we get the
answers that we are looking for. So
please, it's not too late. It's never
too late. Please put your prayer
requests in the chat. Send them to pray
living manner. Church.
Praying is what we do. It's what we love
to do. So let's let's come together and
pray for each other. So some of these
prayer requests are um Sister Matina
Whitehead is asking for prayer for her
daughter Kesha who was admitted to
hospital yesterday.
Sister Zadina is asking for prayer for
her surgery that is coming up shortly.
Um, Seb Grace is asking for prayer for
her and her husband
who is suffering from cancer right now.
As always, we love our brother Taj and
we want to pray for his ministry as well
as his family. Um, Sister Laya Patterson
and Brother West. We are going to be
praying for you guys, as well as Attasha
and her family. Um, Sister Wendy Allen
is asking for prayer for Cassie and her
kids as they need housing. Um, sister
Jamie asks for prayer for all who are
experiencing physical and spiritual
storms as well as sister Tammy and her
three grandchilds, her grandchildren who
are healing from grief from losing her
daughter. Um, sister Vern and her family
for peace as they go through their
individual storms. Um, Sister Charlotte
for her health issues and healing.
Sister Yasina Casus for her brothers and
sisters in Nigeria who are being
prosecuted
and Sister Sarah Jones for divine
intervention in her family. Um so we
notice a lot of health issues, a lot of
people going through storms with their
families and funny enough today pastor
spoke about peace. So as we bring these
prayer requests before God, we ask that
his spirit of peace be with everyone who
would have placed their prayer request
and that he would hear and answer our
prayer. So let's approach God's children
of grace. Heavenly Father, Lord, we want
to thank you. We want to thank you for
because you are God. You are the only
one who we can depend on. You are the
one who loves us even more than we love
our own selves. Dear father, Lord God,
Lord, we want to lift the prayers of our
brothers and sisters before you. Asking
for your healing both physically,
mentally, and emotionally for those who
are going through their storms. Dear
Father, Lord God, we ask that you would
continue to minister to them as they
rely on your strength to not only make
it through, but make it through safely
on the other side and be more strongly
connected to you, dear Father. Lord God,
we ask for you to provide for those who
are in need, those who need jobs, Lord,
those who need housing, those who need
food. Dear father, Lord God, we ask that
you would open your storehouse and pour
out that special blessing upon them.
Dear father, Lord God, I want to lift f
those families who are going through
tumultuous times who are battling with
each other. Dear Father, Lord God, we
ask for your spirit of peace and love to
abide in them and among them, dear
Father, Lord God, that Satan would not
tear them apart, dear Father Lord God,
but they that but that you would
strengthen them so that they can work
together for your name's honor and
glory, dear Father, Lord God. We want to
pray and ask for your protection
for your people who are experiencing
persecution right now dear father Lord
God. Lord you said that we would
experience it Lord but you also promised
that you would be with us in the midst
of it and that you would bring us
through it. So Lord we claim that
promise for them there Father Lord God.
And we ask that you would place your
angels of protection and guard and
guiding around them there, Father Lord
God. That they would continue the work
that you have blessed them to do. Dear,
Father, Lord God, Lord, we want to lift
Pastor Meers and his ministry before you
dear, Lord. Asking that you would
continue to speak through him, dear
Father. Lord God, that your truth would
be heard clearly. That your words would
be spoken through him. not his words but
your words. Dear father, Lord God, I
lift brother Taj and his family as well
before you. Asking that you will
continue to bless his ministry and that
you will continue to keep his family
together and safe. Dear father Lord God,
we ask a special blessing upon the
message that will be shared today. Dear
father, Lord God, I pray that it would
touch our hearts that it would renew our
connection and our conviction in
following you wheresoever you may follow
us, dear father, Lord God. And we ask
that as we as as a people come together
to pray, Lord, that we would pray not
just in our own words, dear Father, Lord
God, but we would pray in your name. we
would pray in accordance with your will
dear father lord god so that you would
hear you would answer and you would
deliver us when we call to you I pray in
Jesus most precious name amen
>> amen Amen. Amen. Amen.
>> I shall not fear
>> the arrow by day.
Nor shall I fear
that say by night
the god of your
>> angel
has set
around me.
Shall not fear.
>> Shall not fear
the arrow by
nor shall I fear
the terror by night.
The God of God
angel
around me.
I shall not fear.
the arrow by
nor shall I fear
the terror by night.
The God
set a cab
around
whom shall I fear?
Who shall
I fear?
Shall I fear?
Whom shall I fear?
You
angel aries
have set in
around me.
>> Who
shall I fear?
>> Who shall I?
Who shall I hear?
>> I
shall I hear
the
cover.
Oh,
>> and
around
me.
>> I'm
not
afraid.
All is well.
I
not
Heat. Heat.
Wat.
You walk me up.
You are me.
Holy
Jesus.
Angelies
the God of God
is the God who
angelies
have set Encampments
>> around me.
>> Encampments
>> Protection
>> around me.
>> His army
>> is all around me.
>> So who
shall
Who shall
>> Stewart?
Hallelujah. Hallelujah. Hallelujah.
Hallelujah. Hallelujah.
Amen. Amen. Happy Sabbath. Welcome
Living Mana Online Church to the Living
Mana online church service. And uh today
we are getting ready to get into the
word of God.
Uh go ahead and put a one in the chat if
you are prepared for living mana. Today
I want to let you know that today's
message
uh entitled what it means to be a 7th
Day Adventist
um is going to be a very challenging
message. Um I'm going to in this message
speak to the idea
uh speak to the concept of what it means
to be a seventh day Adventist and um it
is going to again challenge you. Um you
may think you know what it is what it
means to be a seventh day Adventist and
you may be surprised by the time we're
through with this message. So, I'm going
to invite you to pray. Uh please uh if
you have not yet, share this link. Let
people know the sermon has begun. And
we're going to get into the word of God
this morning. Let's pray. Heavenly
Father,
please speak. Uh Lord,
pour out your word. And Lord, may our
eyes be open. May our hearts be
receptive.
Lord may we be set free by truth today
is our prayer in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
So again the title of the message what
it means to be a 7th day Adventist.
Now,
I became a 7th Day Adventist um in 1994,
and uh it was and is one of the best
decisions, the best decision I've ever
made in my life.
Um,
for those of you who have been
Adventist,
this message is for you because you may
not realize what it actually means to be
a 7th day Adventist. And for those of
you who are not Seventh Day Adventists
and you are you are wanting to learn
more what does it mean to be a Seventh
Day Adventist, this message is for you.
And I believe by the grace of God
um that you're going to see something
very powerful and very moving. So So
what does it mean when someone asks me,
"Hey, you're a 7th Day Adventist. What
is that?"
The way that we typically answer is by
letting those who ask us know, well, you
know, we are Seventh Day Adventists and
this is what we believe. So we kind of
define ourselves
by what we believe. There are certain
set of doctrines
and in the name itself 7th day adventist
it kind of summarizes some of the core
tenants uh of our beliefs. So for
example, seventh day uh we are talking
about we believe that the seventh day
the Sabbath is on the seventh day uh
which is from Friday sundown to Saturday
sundown. So hence the the the name
seventh day and then adventists meaning
we believe in the second advent of Jesus
Christ. And so we we tend to describe
ourselves, right, by the term or by the
doctrines that we that we believe. And
so what are some of those core
doctrines? We're going to talk about
those today. Uh some of those core
doctrines we've just mentioned, the
Sabbath is one, the second coming is
another, and then if I were to ask you
to put in the chat, two or three others,
and I'm just going to go with with three
more. Um we would obviously say that we
have a certain belief when it comes to
the state of the dead. What happens to
an individual when that person dies? We
have a certain belief not only about the
state of the dead but about hellfire,
right? And then uh we believe certain
things about about the punishment of the
wicked and the destruction of the
wicked. And then we have a belief called
the sanctuary. And these are really the
basic tenants and the foundational
uh principles of Adventism. Now, now I
want to speak to these and we're going
to go through these one by one, but not
in the way that you think. I want to
state I want to begin actually with John
8 verse 31 and 32. And I want you to
notice something Jesus said here. Bible
says, "Then said Jesus to those Jews
which believed on him, if you continue
in my word, then are you my disciples
and you shall know the truth and the
truth shall make you free."
That's a very powerful verse right
there, you all. Um Jesus
says that it is imperative for us to
know the truth. But he doesn't stop
there because what he says is knowing
the truth will equal being set free.
Knowing the truth will equal being set
free. So in essence then um
what we believe
ought to have an impact on our
character. In fact
we understand that when we speak of a
name we're talking about character. Name
is synonymous with character. So when
someone says, "I'm a Seventh Day
Adventist," it should not just be about
a set of doctrines that we believe, but
it should also translate into how those
doctrines affect our character, how they
shape our character, and how they in
essence set us free. So y'all put a one
in the chat if that makes sense so far.
Yes. When we when we when we uh um
believe something, a doctrine should not
just be something that is received in
the mind and changes the way that we
think about the Bible, but a doctrine
also ought to have effect upon our
actual characters.
Amen. Amen. So, let's go ahead and begin
to talk about these doctrines. So, one
of the ones we mentioned was the second
coming. Now, we believe that there is a
false teaching on the second coming, and
we believe that teaching is the rapture.
I'm going to talk about that. I actually
preached on this last week, but we're
going to talk about that a little bit.
And I want to show you the difference
between
uh what the Bible teaches about the
second coming and then the false
understanding of the rapture.
So, for example, notice with me John
14:es 1-3. John 14:es 1-3. The Bible
says, "Let not your heart be troubled.
You believe in God, believe also in me.
In my father's house are many mansions.
If it were not so, I would have told
you. I go to prepare a place for you.
And if I go and prepare a place for you,
I will come again and receive you unto
myself, that where I am, there you may
be." Also, Jesus says that he has gone
to prepare a place for us and that he
himself is coming back to get us. And I
like how he starts off when he says,
"Let not your heart be troubled." Why
should we not let our hearts be
troubled? Because he says, "I'm coming
back.
Despite everything you might go through
on this planet, let not your heart be
troubled." Why? because I'm coming back.
And that's why we have hope when it
comes to the second coming. That that
second coming produces hope in the heart
because Jesus says, "Despite the
troubles you may face,
do not be troubled. Let not your heart
be troubled." Why? Because I'm coming
again. I'm coming again personally.
Notice with me John 14 27. He says it
again in the same chapter. Peace I leave
with you. My peace I give unto you. Not
as the world giveth giveth I giveth eye
unto you. Let not your heart be
troubled, neither let it be afraid. Now
this is significant you guys because if
you remember uh in the book of Matthew
chapter 24, Jesus begins to talk about
this this uh event that will come up on
the world at the end of time. And and he
talks about uh uh the signs of his
coming. And I want you to notice what he
says in Matthew chapter 24. He says he,
the Bible says, he sat upon the Mount of
Olives. The disciples came unto him
privately, saying, Tell us, when shall
these things be, and what shall be the
sign of thy coming and of the end of the
world?
And Jesus said and answered unto them,
Take heed that no man deceive you. For
many shall come in my name, saying, I am
Christ, and shall deceive many, and you
shall hear of wars and rumors of wars.
See that you be not troubled, for all
these things must come to pass, but the
end is not yet. Not only does G does
Jesus say, see that you be not troubled,
and we tie that back into to John
chapter 14. Why? Because we know that
he's coming again. We have this hope
that Jesus is coming again. So don't be
troubled. Even listen to me. Even when
in the Bible in Daniel 12:1 where the
Bible says, "And at that time shall
Michael stand up, the great prince which
standeth for the children of thy people,
and there shall be a time of trouble
such as never was since there was a
nation even to that same time. And at
that time thy people shall be delivered,
everyone that shall be found written in
the book." Do you see the cycle here?
Jesus says, "Even though there's coming
a time of trouble that has never been,
do not be troubled." Why? Because my
people will be delivered. How are they
going to be delivered? When Jesus comes
again to take them that where he is,
there they may be also. So, the reason
we have hope
in the second coming is because Jesus
says, "I'm coming to deliver you out of
all your troubles." I like how Psalm
Psalmsapter 9:9 says that the Lord also
will be a refuge for the oppressed, a
refuge in times of trouble. And Psalm
27:5, "For in the time of trouble, he
shall hide me in his pavilion. In the
secret of his tabernacle shall he hide
me, and he shall set me upon a rock." As
Seventh Day Adventists, we have this
hope that Jesus is coming again. And now
let me share with you what it means when
the Bible says Jesus is coming again.
What the Bible says, how the Bible
describes the second coming of Jesus.
Notice with me Revelation 1:7. If I were
to ask you uh uh 7th day Adventist, what
do we believe about the second coming?
You would say Revelation 17, behold, he
cometh with clouds, and every eye shall
see him. They also which pierced him,
and all the kindreds of the earth shall
wail because of him. So, we know that
when Jesus comes, he comes with the
clouds.
We know that when he comes, every eye
sees him. Put a one in the chat if that
makes sense so far. Not only does when
Jesus comes, he comes with the clouds
and every eye sees him. But the Bible
says in John 5:2, "Verily, verily, I say
unto you, the hour is coming, and now is
when the dead shall hear the voice of
the Son of God, and they that hear shall
live." When Jesus comes again, the
righteous
are brought to life.
Amen. When Jesus comes again, the
righteous are brought to life. Notice
with me what else happens when Jesus
comes again. In 2 Thessalonians chapter
2 verse 8 and 9, the Bible says, "And
then shall that wicked be revealed, whom
the Lord shall consume with the spirit
of his mouth and shall destroy with the
brightness of his coming, even him whose
coming is after the working of Satan
with all power and signs and lying
wonders. When Jesus comes again, the
wicked perish." We see this again in
Matthew 24 37-4. But as the days of Noah
were, so shall also the coming of the
Son of Man be. For as in the days that
were before the flood, they were eating
and drinking, marrying and giving in
marriage until the day Noah entered into
the ark and knew not until the flood
came and took them all away. So shall
also the coming of the Son of Man be.
Then shall two be in the field. One
shall be taken
and the other left. So guys, let's recap
for a second. When Jesus comes again, he
comes with the clouds.
Every eye sees him.
The righteous are brought to life
and the wicked are destroyed.
We also find that when Jesus comes
again, Satan will be bound. Notice with
me Revelation 20:es 1 and two. I saw an
angel come down from heaven having the
key of the bottomless pit and a great
chain in his hand. and he laid hold on
the dragon, that old serpent, which the
which is the devil and Satan, and bound
him a thousand years. I want you to note
how much happens when Jesus comes again.
Notice again with me in Matthew 24:30
that Jesus when he comes again, he comes
with power and glory. The Bible says,
"And then shall appear the sign of the
Son of Man in heaven, and then shall all
the tribes of the earth mourn, and they
shall see the son of man coming in the
clouds of heaven with power and great
glory."
You guys, there is so much happening
when Jesus comes again the second time
that it cannot be mistaken. It cannot be
mistaken. Notice again with me, I'm
going to show you three more things.
Notice with me in 1 Corinthians 15:51,
the Bible says, "Behold, I show you a
mystery. We shall not all sleep, but we
shall all be changed in a moment, in the
twinkling of an eye at the last trump.
For the trumpet shall sound, and the
dead shall be raised incorruptible, and
we shall be changed." When Jesus comes
again, we are changed
into his likeness.
We are changed to be like him. That's
why we look forward to the second coming
of Jesus Christ. Again, in 1
Thessalonians chapter 4 16 and 17, the
Bible says, "For the Lord himself shall
descend from heaven with a shout, with
the voice of the archangel, and with the
trump of God, and the dead in Christ
shall rise first. Then we which are
alive and remain shall be caught up
together with them in the clouds to meet
the Lord in the air. And so shall we
ever be with the Lord. All right
everybody. So we have just seen that
when Jesus comes again, every eye sees
him. He comes with the clouds. The
wicked are destroyed. The righteous are
brought to life. We are caught up
together in the clouds with him. We are
changed in a moment.
Those
are some very powerful things happening
you guys. Satan is bound and is not
allowed to run loose and cause havoc. He
is bound for a thousand years. Now this
is the true and genuine teaching of the
second coming. There is a counterfeit to
this and it is called the secret
rapture.
And in this secret rapture teaching, it
basically teaches number one that when
Christ comes, his his coming is
invisible.
It's invisible. That's a false teaching,
you guys. It's a false teaching. Number
two, uh uh that it is a secret that
people are not going to know. People are
not going to be able to recognize that
it was the coming of Christ. Number
three, Satan will still be on the loose.
Satan will still be going about doing
his thing, you know, with this seven
years or three and a half years of of
tribulation. And number four,
sin and deception
continue.
That is a abs. That's an unbiblical
teaching regarding how Jesus returns.
That is not in the Bible. Now, let's put
that aside for a moment. And I want you
to notice something else. Along with the
second coming of Jesus Christ is the
ultimate destruction of the wicked, what
we call hellfire.
And and I want you to note with me
uh that the Bible tells us in Revelation
20:14 and 15, "And death and hell were
cast into the lake of fire. This is the
second death. And whosoever was not
found written in the book of life was
cast into the lake of fire." As Seventh
Day Adventists, we believe what exactly
what Malachi 4:es 1-3 states. For
behold, the day cometh that shall burn
as an oven, and all the proud, yay, all
that do wickedly shall be stubble. And
the day that cometh shall burn them up,
sayeth the Lord of hosts, that it shall
leave them neither root nor branch. But
unto you that fear my name shall the son
of righteousness arise with healing in
his wings. And you shall go forth and
grow up as calves and a stalls.
And you shall tread down the wicked for
they shall be ashes under the souls of
your feet in the day that I shall do
this saith the Lord of hosts. We believe
according to the Bible that when the
wicked are destroyed, there is nothing
left of them. The fire totally consumes
the wicked.
God does not punish the wicked
throughout all eternity. They are turned
into ashes. There is nothing left. Put
up one in the chat if you believe that
when Jesus comes again, when Jesus comes
again, every eye sees him. Uh uh the the
dead are ra the righteous dead are
raised. The wicked are are put to death.
Uh, Satan is bound. We are caught up
together in the clouds to meet the Lord
with the air. He comes and every eye
sees him. He comes with the clouds of
heaven.
Put a one in the chat if you believe
that when the wicked are ultimately
destroyed. There is nothing left of
them. The fire totally consumes them.
That is a teaching of hellfire.
And then I want you to know this
because connected with the second with
the with the teaching of the second
coming is the understanding of what
happens to a person when they die.
There's a reason Jesus is going to
resurrect the dead. If they were in
heaven right now, what would be the
purpose of them being resurrected if
they are in heaven? And why would they
want the old decrepit bodies left here
on earth if their spirits are in heaven?
No. As Seventh Day Adventists, we
believe according to Ecclesiastes
chapter 9:5, "For the living know that
they shall die, but the dead know not
anything. Neither have they anymore a
reward, for the memory of them is
forgotten." This is what we believe.
Verse six says, "Also, their love, and
their hatred, and their envy is now
perished. Neither have they anymore a
portion forever in anything that is done
under the sun." We believe that when a
person dies, they are asleep in the
grave. They know nothing. They are
absolutely
perished. They are absolutely not, let
me not use the word perish. They are
absolutely unconscious. They know
nothing.
They can feel nothing.
And they will remain in that state until
Jesus comes to take them home. they are
asleep.
The counterfeit of this is that when the
dead die, they just live on. They they
don't really die. There's no such thing
as death. They just transition from one
form of life to another. So, they
continue to live on just as a
counterfeit of the true teaching of
hellfire is that the wicked burn forever
and ever and ever and ever.
And then we believe in the seventh day
Sabbath.
We believe that God created man in his
image. That God created the world. He He
created the world in six days and he
rested on the seventh day. We believe
this. We do not believe the counterfeit
that because of the New Testament, the
Sabbath was changed from the last day of
the week to the first day of the week.
There is no evidence in the Bible to
suggest this whatsoever. And finally, we
believe in this thing called the
sanctuary. Daniel 8 chapter 14 Exodus
25:8 uh uh the New Testament 1
Corinthians 1 Corinthians chapter 3 uh
the book of Hebrews speaks about a
sanctuary and we believe that in that
sanctuary the plan of salvation is
unfolding and God ultimately will
cleanse that sanctuary before he comes
again and this is what it means to be a
seventh day Adventist
This is what we believe. Now,
if you were watching and you were you
are not a Seventh Day Adventist,
that part of the message was for you.
What is coming next is also for you. If
you're like, man, I've never heard these
teachings before, but this is really
intriguing. Very good. What's coming
next is also for you, but it is
definitely for those who call themselves
Seventh Day Adventists.
And here's why I need you to because you
may have been like, "I know this. I know
this. I got this, pastor. I got it. I
got it. I got it. I know it. I'm a
Seventh Day Adventist."
But remember the the first verse that we
read, which was, "You shall know the
truth."
Not period. You shall know the truth.
All right, we're good to go. You know
the truth. You shall know the truth, and
the truth shall set you free.
If the truth,
if the doctrine does not have an effect
on our character, we do not yet
understand what it means to be a seventh
day Adventist. Come on, let's break it
down. See, here's what I want you to
understand.
If you are keeping the Sabbath
as a sign in remembering what God did
back at the creation,
if that is the only reason you are
keeping the Sabbath, you do not yet
understand the purpose of the Sabbath.
I want you to understand
that yes, we are to commemorate
what God did back there at creation.
In fact, if we go to the Bible and we go
to the book of Exodus 20:8, remember the
Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six days
shalt thou labor and do all thy work.
But the seventh day is a Sabbath of the
Lord thy God. In it, thou shalt not do
any work. Thou nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, thy manservant, nor thy
maidervant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth and all that in the maze uh the
sea and all that in the maze and rested
the seventh day. Wherefore the Lord
blessed the Sabbath day and hallowed.
Here's what I need you to understand.
Here's what I need you to grasp.
The Sabbath is the sign of God's
creative power. Now the Bible se tells
us in 2 Corinthians, if any man be in
Christ, he is a new creation. Meaning
meaning
that the other reason we ought to be
keeping the Sabbath is not just because
of God's creative power back there at
creation week, but it is also a sign of
God's creative power in you. Let me
break it down for you. You see, just as
God, that very creation came upon a
world that was without form and void,
you need to remember, I hope you
remember, I hope this is the case that
before God entered into your life, you
your life was was without form and void.
Chaos was on the face of the deep. And
then and then if by the grace of God the
spirit of God began to move upon you and
God said let there be light day one and
then led you into baptism through the
waters day two and then started to
produce fruit uh uh in you day three and
then gave you h the son of righteousness
as your new guiding light day four and
then said I'm I'm calling to make you a
fisher of men day five and then
recreates you in his image and in his
likeness day six then beloved
The Sabbath for you is a sign that God
has recreated you.
And if you have not experienced that
recreation,
meaning if you're still the same you
that you were before the spirit of God
moved upon the face of the waters,
before the spirit of God moved upon you,
if you're still getting mad at people,
if you're still cursing people out, if
you're still acting like the chaotic,
the chaos back there before God began
creating, then you may be going to
church on Saturday, but you are not
keeping the Sabbath.
The Sabbath has not become real to you.
The Sabbath has not become a sign to
you. The Sabbath is the sign
that God has recreated you. And if you
haven't been recreated, then the sign is
a counterfeit sign.
The sign itself is not counterfeit, but
but what it signifies has not happened.
And if what it's supposed to signify has
not happened, you're not actually
keeping the Sabbath. Are you really a
seventh day Adventist?
Please understand that there's another
reason given in the book of Deuteronomy.
Deuteronomy chapter 5. The Sabbath is
here mentioned again, but now with a
different reason. Keep the Sabbath day
to sanctified as the Lord thy God has
commanded thee. Sixth day shalt thou
labor and do all thy work. But the
seventh day is a Sabbath of the Lord thy
God. In it thou shalt not do any work.
Thou nor thy son, nor thy daughter, nor
thy man's servant, nor thy maid servant,
nor thy ox, nor thine ass, nor any of
thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is
within thy gates, that thy man's servant
and thy maidervant may rest as well as
thou. Watch this. And remember that thou
was a servant in the land of Egypt, and
that the Lord thy God brought thee out
thence through a mighty hand by a
stretched out arm. Therefore the Lord
thy God commanded thee to keep the
Sabbath day. Please understand
that the Sabbath was also a sign of
deliverance from the house of bondage.
That's what Egypt meant. The house of
bondage. The Sabbath, beloved, is a sign
that God has set you free
from the house of bondage. Meaning, if
you are still spiritually living in
Egypt, if you are still bound to the old
ways and bound to your old habits, if
you're still bound
by the things of this world, you may be
going to church on the right day of the
week, but you are not yet keeping the
Sabbath.
The truth has not yet set you free.
Are y'all understanding what I'm saying
here?
You can celebrate the anniversary of
something.
But if the thing never happened, there's
no anniversary.
If you haven't been set free, if you're
not out of Egypt, remember the children
of Israel didn't keep the Sabbath in
Egypt. They couldn't. God said to Moses,
"Deliver them out of Egypt so that they
can obey me."
And it is only after they came out of
Egypt that God gives them the Sabbath to
keep. They couldn't keep it in Egypt
while they were in bondage. Pharaoh
would not let them.
In the very same way, beloved,
it is only when we become that former
liar, that former thief, the former
drunkard, the former murderer, the
former you fill in the blank. It is only
as we become the former of the we are no
we are no longer that thing. We are out.
We we have left that life. We have left
that bondage. Then beloved, the Sabbath
becomes something to celebrate. You have
something to celebrate.
You're not just celebrating that God
created the world back there and say,
"Oh, well, okay, that's great. God, no,
no, no. Yes, God created the world back
then, but you're celebrating that that
same power that created the world back
then is the same power that has
recreated you now. And if that power is
not active in you, then you have nothing
to celebrate. You may be going to church
on the seventh day of the week and not
yet actually be a seventh day Adventist.
That's the Sabbath. But remember, there
is also the second coming. There is also
the second coming. You'll remember
that the children of Israel were not
delivered out of bondage until the Lord
came down. Let's read it. Exodus 3:7.
The Lord said, "I have surely seen the
affliction of my people which are in
Egypt, and have heard their cry by
reason of their task masters, for I know
their sorrows, and I am come down. I am
come down to deliver them out of the
hand of the Egyptians." I want you to
understand that that that God came down
and it was his coming that delivered
them out of bondage. So here is my
question.
Jesus said that when he left, he was
coming again.
But he told them that he would come
again through the spirit. Let Come on.
Come on. Let me show you. John 14:1 17.
Even the spirit of truth whom the world
cannot receive because it see him not,
neither knoweth him. But you know him,
for he dwelleth with you and shall be in
you. I will not leave you comfortless. I
will come to you. So let me ask you a
question.
Does Jesus come to us again through his
spirit? Yes or no?
Yes, he does. Yes, he does. That's why
he sends the comforter. And the purpose
of the comforter is to is to allow us to
receive
Christ
within us.
Now, beloved, remember what I told you.
Remember what we learned earlier.
The doctrine
must have a practical effect on the
character.
So beloved,
we believe that the second coming of
Jesus
will happen that it is yet future. But
at the same time, beloved, there is a
second coming of Jesus that must occur
before that second coming of Jesus. And
that is that Jesus says, "I will come to
you." And he comes to you through the
spirit, which by the way was manifested
in the Old Testament as the cloud.
Did I say that when Jesus comes again,
did the Bible say that when Jesus comes
again, the clouds will come with him?
That he will come with the clouds?
Beloved, let me frame it this way. If we
if we want to be ready for the second
coming of Jesus, we must first
experience the second coming of Jesus.
Can I say that again? If you want to be
ready for the second coming of Jesus,
where he literally comes in the sky, you
must first have experienced the second
coming of Jesus, where he comes through
the spirit into your heart. Are y'all
with me? Do you understand what I'm
saying?
The second coming of Christ, beloved,
changes your life. The second coming of
Christ, beloved, changes your character.
The second coming of Christ, beloved,
relieves you, delivers you from trouble.
Let not your heart be troubled. Why?
Because if Jesus has come to you again,
the second time through his spirit, he
is preparing you for when he comes the
second time in the flesh. The Bible says
in Revelation 1:7 again, we'll read it.
Behold, he cometh with clouds, and
every eye shall see him. Pause for a
second, everybody. Pause for a second.
When Jesus comes again, does every eye
see him?
Yes. Yes.
Yes. Every eye sees him. I hope y'all
don't I hope you do not miss this,
y'all. When Jesus comes again, every eye
sees him. It is not an invisible thing.
people will know in the same way when
Jesus enters into you.
It is not an invisible thing. That is a
false doctrine. It is not a secret
thing. That is a false doctrine. If
people cannot see it, then it is not
real.
If people cannot see Christ in you,
then Christ is not in you.
When Jesus comes again
the second time, every eye sees him. In
the same way, when Jesus comes again
through his spirit, when he comes into
us, every eye will be, "Man, something's
different about you.
You talk different. You act different.
You everything. What's changed about
you? It's Jesus.
I see Jesus in you." And so, beloved,
I'm telling you, if you are a Seventh
Day Adventist and people do not see
Jesus in you,
you are living a false doctrine.
You are living a secret rapture.
And Jesus said, "Listen, if they say
he's in the desert, in the secret place,
don't believe it.
Do not believe it.
When Jesus comes again, beloved,
everything changes about you. When Jesus
comes again, every eye sees it. The
Bible says in Matthew chap Matthew
5:14-16,
"You are the light of the world. A city
set on a hill cannot be hid, neither do
men light a candle and put it under a
bushel, but on a candlestick, and it
giveth light unto all that are in the
house. Let your light so shine that men
may see your good works and glorify your
father which is in heaven. It is false
doctrine, beloved. It is false doctrine
to believe that when Jesus comes, it's a
secret. If you secretly have Jesus in
you, you do not have Jesus in you.
Do I need to say it again? If you
secretly have Jesus in you, you do not
have Jesus in you. If Jesus is in you,
it will be seen. The Bible tells us, the
Bible tells us
uh uh in Matthew 20 27, for there shall
arise false Christ and false prophets,
and shall show great signs and wonders
in so much that if it were possible,
they shall deceive the very elect.
Behold, I've told you, if they say unto
you, he's in the desert, go not forth.
He is in the secret chambers. Believe it
not. Why? For as lightning cometh out of
the east and shineth even unto the west.
So also, so also will people be able to
look at you and be like, "Yep, Jesus is
obviously in him. Jesus is obviously in
her. This person has obviously
experienced
the second coming of Jesus. I'm not
talking about the literal second coming.
I'm talking about Jesus coming into the
heart. I'm talking about Jesus coming
into your life and manifesting himself
in you. So now note with me beloved,
note how first John chapter 4 verse 2
and three tells us this. The Bible says
hereby know you the spirit of God. Every
spirit that confessth that Jesus Christ
is come in the flesh is of God. And
every spirit that confesseth not that
Jesus Christ is come in the flesh is not
of God. And this is that spirit of
antichrist whereof you have heard that
it should come and even now is already
in the world. Listen, do you understand
what it means to confess that Jesus
Christ is come in the flesh? What it
means, beloved, is not did Jesus really
walk on the earth? Yes, that is part of
it. But what the text is actually
telling us
is that Jesus Christ must come in my
flesh
and your flesh. And if you have not
confessed Jesus in your flesh, which is
not something you simply do with your
mouth, it will be seen.
And if you are not confessing Christ in
your life,
then the Bible says that is a spirit of
antichrist.
It's a powerful statement.
Powerful statement
from an author who wrote these words. We
do not understand God's sufficiency. He
will reveal himself in our hearts. When
we confess that Jesus Christ is come in
the flesh, we are to confess that he has
come in our flesh. We have laid our own
sins, laid aside our own sins, and we
are living to the glory of God. I need
you to understand, beloved, that the the
the understanding of the Sabbath and the
understanding of the second coming of
Christ is not just to change our minds
about how Jesus comes again. It is
actually the doctrine is designed to
teach us deeper spiritual truths.
We understand that when Jesus comes
again the second time, the wicked perish
at the brightness of his coming.
If that is so,
if that is true, and it is true,
then when Jesus comes again to you, the
old wicked man, the old wicked self
perishes at the brightness of his
coming. Why? Because he's coming with
power and glory. And if he's coming with
power and glory, the old man cannot
withstand or cannot stand in the
presence of that power and glory. So if
you have experienced the second coming
of Christ, the Bible tells us in Romans
chapter 6:4, I'll let the Bible say it.
Therefore, we are buried with him by
baptism into death, that like as Christ
was raised up from the dead by the glory
of the father, even so we also should
walk in newness of life. For if we have
been planted together in the likeness of
his death, we shall also be in the
likeness of his resurrection, knowing
this, that our old man is crucified with
him, that the body of sin might be
destroyed, that henceforth we should not
serve sin. I need you to understand,
when Jesus comes again, the righteous
are resurrected.
When Jesus comes again, the righteous
are resurrected. Which means, beloved,
that if Jesus comes in you, the old man
dies and the new man lives. The old man
is put to death and the new man is
raised up in righteousness. If we want
to experience that literally at the
second coming of Christ, when the when
when the dead in Christ are raised from
the grave, we must first experience it
spiritually in the heart.
Are y'all following what I'm saying so
far? Give me a five in the chat if
you're saying, "Pastor, we are with
you." I need you to understand that the
righteous come to life, the wicked
perish.
The wicked perish. Not only that, you
remember John chapter 1 vers12. But as
many as received him, to them gave he
power to become the sons of God,
even to them that believe on his name,
which were born not of blood, nor of the
will of flesh, nor of the will of man,
but of God. Yes, beloved, when Jesus
comes again, he's coming with power and
he gives us that power. He allow he he
grants us that power. So the power and
glory that he comes with is designed to
destroy the old man in me. Have you
experienced the second coming of Christ?
Are you really a seventh day Adventist?
Have the doctrines
set you free? Have the truth
set you free? Because beloved, if the
truth points to Jesus, then I need you
to understand that the Sabbath and the
state of the dead and and and the
teaching of heaven, all of these things
are designed to show us an aspect of
Christ that must be manifested in the
life.
The doctrines are not just to be
believed here. They're not just designed
to change the way we think about the
Bible, but they're designed to change
our characters. So then,
in the same way that we were told that
when Jesus comes again, we shall be
changed in a moment, in the twinkling of
an eye. Note with me, beloved, what
Romans 12:2 says. Be ye transformed
by the renewing of your mind, and be not
conformed to this world, but be ye
transformed that you may prove what is
that good and acceptable and perfect
will of God. When Jesus comes again,
beloved, we are to be changed in a
moment, in the twinkling of an eye, by
faith.
That is what the teaching of
justification by faith is. God forgives
us. He says, "I have set you free. Now
walk in that freedom. The former things
have passed away."
This is why Ephesians chapter 4 22 says
that you put off concerning the former
conversation, the old man which is
corrupt according to the deceitfulness
of lust and be re be renewed in the
spirit of your mind and put on the new
man which after God is created in
righteousness and true holiness.
Wherefore put away lying, speak every
man truth with his neighbor. For we are
members one of another. Are you
understanding what I'm saying?
Beloved, these doctrinal teachings that
we often teach others, oh, this is how
Christ comes again. And when the when he
comes again, oh, these are all the
things that are going to happen.
If those things are not manifested in
our lives,
I fear we do not yet understand what it
actually means to be a 7th day
Adventist. God is not just concerned
with what we think about the doctrine,
but he desires the teachings to have an
effect, an actual change, transformation
on the character. And listen, just as we
learned that at the second coming of
Christ, the dead are raised up into
heaven. Please note with me what
Ephesians chapter 2:4 says, "But God,
who is rich in mercy, for his great love
were loved us, even when we were dead in
sins, has he quickened, that means made
alive together with Christ by grace are
you saved, and has raised us up together
and made us sit together in heavenly
places in Christ Jesus." Beloved, by
faith, we are to be living in heavenly
places. Now, why? Because we experienced
the second coming of Christ. The dead,
the the wicked died at the brightness
and power of his of his glory, and the
righteous was raised not only to life,
but raised to live in heavenly places.
Are y'all following what I'm saying? And
it is this, beloved, that we celebrate
in the Sabbath. I'm a new creature. Why?
because God delivered me from the from
the bondage of this world. And now I'm
living in heavenly places. I've been set
free from the Egypt of this world. And
thus, every seventh day that rolls
around, I am reminded of how God
delivered me. Not just what God did so
many years ago, way back there in
creation, but what he is doing in my
life now. Are you really a Seventh Day
Adventist? Notice with me Colossians
chapter 1 verse3. If you then be risen
with Christ,
that happens at the second coming,
y'all.
If you then be risen with Christ, seek
those things which are above, where
Christ siteth on the right hand of God.
Set your affection on things above and
not on things on the earth. Beloved,
have you experienced the second coming
of Jesus into your heart? Has he come
again into your heart? Have you received
him? He is standing at the door knocking
and he wants to come into your heart.
But unless you experience the second
coming of Christ here, you will not
experience the second coming of Christ
when it literally happens again. In
fact,
we learned at Seventh Day Adventist that
when Jesus comes again,
when Jesus comes again, the devil is
bound.
Yes. Yes, I said it. When Jesus comes
again, y'all, the devil is bound. How
many of you would like to have the devil
bound from your life?
I need you to understand, beloved, that
when Jesus comes again, the devil has no
jurisdiction
over you. He is bound
and he may threaten you and he may still
try to tempt and do all the things that
he usually does. But beloved, when
Christ is in you, the devil's hands are
bound. There is a great chain put about
him. Let us read it again. And I saw an
angel come down from heaven, having the
key of the bottomless pit, and a great
chain in his hand. And he laid hold on
the dragon, that old serpent, which is
the devil, and Satan, and bound him a
thousand years, and set a seal upon him,
and shut him up that he should deceive
the nations no more. Listen to me, you
guys. When Jesus comes into your life,
the devil can't deceive you anymore. He
can't pull the wool over your eyes
anymore. He can't get away with the
stuff he used to get away. He is bound.
He has no authority in your life.
I need you to understand, beloved, that
these teachings, these doctrines,
beloved, are not just given to us to
help us understand what's going to
happen better so that we cannot be
deceived by false doctrine, but they are
given to actually change the character.
And what it really means to be a Seventh
Day Adventist is that these teachings
have affected your character so that you
are no longer living in the chaos of a
precreation.
You
you are living as a recreated being in
Christ who has experienced the second
coming in your heart. The wicked man in
you has died and the righteous has come
to life. He is living in heavenly
places. Satan is bound. Every eye sees
the glory of and power of God dwelling
in you. It's not a secret. He has come
with the cloud in your heart. He has
come with the spirit and every eye can
see it and the devil is bound from you.
I want you to notice once again another
very powerful statement. Another very
powerful statement. Notice with me, God
wants us to be wide awake that when he
shall come, we shall be ready to say,
"Lo, this is our God. We have waited for
him and he will save us. He is coming to
us by his holy spirit today.
Let us recognize him now. Then we shall
recognize him when he comes in the
clouds of heaven with power and great
glory. See, y'all thought I was making
stuff up.
Y'all thought I was making stuff up.
And what I'm telling you, church,
is that it is not sufficient enough to
say, "I'm a Seventh Day Adventist simply
because I believe in the second coming
of Jesus. I believe that the Sabbath is
on the seventh day of the week. I
believe that when the dead die uh that
when Jesus comes again uh uh the dead
will be raised and the wicked will be
the the righteous will be raised and the
wicked will be will be will be
destroyed. It's not enough to just say
those things and believe those things.
Those things must become reality in us.
Come on y'all. Let's talk for a moment
about the second death. We are almost
there you guys. We got just a few more
doctrines to cover. We've covered this
the the the the second coming of Jesus.
We've covered the Sabbath. Now, let's
just talk about the state of the dead
real quick. Let's talk about the the
punishment of the wicked very quickly.
See,
uh uh the Bible says that the that the
wicked are going to suffer the second
death. The wicked are going to suffer
the second death. Romans chapter 6 vers
23 tells us this. For the wages of sin
is death, but the gift of God is eternal
life through Jesus Christ our Lord. Back
in Genesis 2:1 17, God had told Adam and
Eve, "But of the tree of the knowledge
of good and evil, thou shalt not eat of
it. For in the day thou eatest thereof,
thou shalt surely die." And when Adam
and Eve ate from that tree, sin entered
the world. But because of God's grace,
notice with me, Romans chapter 5 verse,
but God commended his love toward us in
that while we were yet sinners, Christ
died for us. Christ died for us. And I
want you to notice this. In Galatians
3:27, the Bible says, "For as many of
you of you have been baptized into into
Christ have put on Christ." Now I want
to break something down to you beloved
about this idea of the second death. The
second death is total destruction of the
wicked.
See
we were all we are all destined to die.
Every man must taste death.
Generally speaking every man must taste
taste death. I'm not going going to go
into the prophetic uh implications of of
those there there will be those who are
alive when Jesus comes again who will
not taste death. But if we're not a part
of that that group when that time when
Jesus comes, every man must taste taste
death.
Now the wicked suffer the second death.
We read that a little bit earlier in
Revelation chapter 20.
And that second death we have learned is
absolute destruction of the wicked.
The fires of hell are going to destroy
the wicked.
You say, "Pastor, well, how does that
become relevant to me?" Well, here's
what I want you to understand.
The Bible tells us uh uh again, Romans
6, Romans 6, uh verse one, what shall we
say then? Shall we continue in sin that
grace may abound? God forbid. How shall
we that are dead to sin live any longer
therein? Know you not that so many of us
were baptized into Jesus Christ were
baptized into his death. Therefore we
are buried with him by baptism into
death. That like as Christ was raised
from the dead by the glory of the
father, even so we should also walk in
newness of life. For if we have been
planted together in the likeness of his
death, we shall also be in the likeness
of his resurrection. Knowing this that
our old man is crucified with him that
the body of sin might be destroyed.
Pause for a second you guys.
Baptism is another death.
Meaning we all have to die that first
death. But Jesus offers us another
death.
Jesus offers us another death. He says,
"Listen, if you're baptized in me, you
are being baptized into my death, and
that death is going to serve as your
second death." What do you mean, pastor?
Listen, listen. Let me break it down to
you. I want you to notice with me how
how John puts it. John said in Matthew
chap in in in Matthew chapter 3:1, "I
indeed baptize you with water unto
repentance, but he that cometh after me
is mightier than I, whose shoes I'm not
worthy to bear. He shall baptize you
with the Holy Ghost and with fire,
whose fan is in his hand, and he will
thoroughly purge his floor and gather
his wheat into the garner, but he will
burn up the chaff with unquenchable
fire." Please listen to me, you guys. Do
you understand that when you are being
baptized
in fire
that this is God
spiritually burning the old man to
death?
This is God.
This is his fire destroying the old man.
what Romans just call the body of this
of of of sin, the old man crucified dead
through the baptism of Christ. In other
words, beloved,
the biblical teaching of hellfire is
that there is nothing but ashes left of
the wicked man. Which means, beloved,
when Jesus comes into your life and you
are experiencing that that that that
that moving from chaos before creation
to a new creation in Christ, you're
you're you're keeping the Sabbath
because you have been resurrected and
living in heavenly places. The fire of
the spirit of baptism has burned up the
old man.
When we say uh there was a church fire,
what we mean is the church was set on
fire and burnt down. When we say there
was a house fire, what we mean is the
house was set on fire and it burnt down.
So when the Bible talks about hellfire,
when the Bible talks about hellfire,
beloved, what we must understand from
this is that it is the fire of God
burning hell down. And you see many of
us have hell bound in us. And God is
trying to burn that hell
out of us.
He would rather destroy the old man with
the fire of his glory and presence
through the spirit than have to do it
literally at the end of time. So he's
saying listen die your second death now.
That'll be your second death. But for
those who are those who reject Christ,
those who are never born again, no, your
second death will be at the end of time
because you never chose the death I
offered you through Christ.
I need you to understand, beloved, that
if you have experienced the second
coming of Christ into your life, you
have also experienced a second death.
meaning not just the death that we
experience at the grave, but you also
died with Christ and in that you were
baptized with unquenchable fire, the
fire of God's love. Listen, come on.
Isaiah 4:4.
This is why the Bible says, "When the
Lord shall have washed away the filth of
the daughters of Zion and shall have
purged the blood of Jerusalem from the
midst thereof by the spirit of judgment
and the spirit of burning." In Malachi
chapter 3, it says, "But who may abide
the day of his coming? And who shall
stand when he appearth? For he is like a
refiner's fire and like fuller soap, and
he shall sit as a refiner and a purifier
of silver. and he shall purify the sons
of Levi and purge them as gold and
silver that they may offer an offering
of righteousness unto the Lord. I need
you to understand
these doctrines, beloved,
are not just to teach us about what
happens to the wicked in the fires of
hell at the end of time. It is also to
show us that if we are baptized in
Christ, his fire is designed to burn the
old man to ashes so that there is
nothing left of him. God wants to see
nothing left of you. Let the fire do its
work.
Let the fire do its work. You can either
be d you can either allow the old man to
be stro destroyed now or you can wait
until that that lake of fire to be
literally destroyed then.
Beloved, what it means to be a seventh
day Adventist is not just it is not just
an understanding of our doctrines. It is
understanding that the doctrines when
rightly understood are designed to
actually have an effect on our
characters.
Let me talk about two more things. The
state of the dead. We know that what the
Bible says when a man dies, he knows
nothing. His love, his hatred, his envy
is perished. He has no more portion in
anything that is done under the sun.
Beloved, if this is true and we believe
that it is true, then when the old man
dies,
he should not be resurrected.
The old man, his love and his hatred is
perished.
That's what happens when death actually
takes place. your love, the things you
used to love, the things you used to
hate, all of those things are perished,
are gone.
And so the question now is, is the old
man really dead or has he only been
mistaken
for dead?
You know when Jesus was on the cross and
they weren't sure if he was dead or not
and the Roman soldier took a sword and
pierced his side
and he didn't respond and that's how
they knew that he was dead
because if he would have if he was alive
he would have reacted
but the way they knew he was dead was
that he didn't respond.
Are y'all catching this guys? The way
they knew he was dead was that he didn't
respond.
How will the world know that we are
truly dead in Christ?
That we are dead and Christ is living in
us.
It's when we learn not to respond, you
guys.
It's when we don't allow the devil to
get that response out of us.
That is when we're truly living. I am
crucified with Christ. Nevertheless, yet
I live. Yet not I, but Christ liveth in
me.
I need you to understand, beloved, that
a mere mental ascent to the doctrines of
our church does not actually make it may
make you a seventh day Adventist on the
books.
But to have your name written on the
books of the church is not the same as
having your name written on the books in
heaven.
A mere mental ascent
means nothing
if the truth does not set us free.
One more point,
that's sanctuary doctrine.
That's sanctuary teaching. We believe
that that the law of God
is is written in the temple.
And we believe that
God began a cleansing process at the end
of the 2300 days and that
that before he comes again, the
sanctuary will be cleansed.
The Bible tells us
in 1 Corinthians, "Know ye not that you
are the temple of the Holy Ghost and
that the spirit of God dwells in you?"
It is not enough to mentally believe the
doctrine of the sanctuary
if we do not understand that just as the
law of God in the Old Testament was
written in the temple, so Jesus has come
to write the law of God in our temples.
If we do not understand that the purpose
of the sanctuary, the purpose of
cleansing the sanctuary was to remove
the sins from the temple. If we don't
understand that God is also wanting to
cleanse our sanctuary, that the teaching
of the cleansing of a heavenly sanctuary
is really the teaching of God cleansing
our sanctuaries.
If our sanctuaries are filthy and yet we
can believe all day long in what
happened in 1844 and we can believe all
day long that Jesus when he entered into
heaven entered into a into a sanctuary
and we can believe all day long that
there's a first phase of the sanctuary
and a second phase of the sanctuary. We
can believe that all day long, beloved.
But if this sanctuary isn't being
cleansed, we do not yet understand
what it actually means to be a seventh
day Adventist.
I close with this thought.
Jesus says, "I stand at the door and
knock."
Why?
Because it's the second coming that sets
everything off, you guys.
It is the second coming of Christ that
ushers in that that millennial Sabbath.
It's the second coming of Christ that
causes the wicked, the the the the old
man to die. It is the second coming of
Christ that causes the righteous to come
to life. It is the second coming of
Christ that causes the righteous to be
caught up into heavenly places. It is
the second coming of Christ that causes
Satan to be bound out of the life. It is
the second coming of Christ, beloved,
that that that ultimately brings about
the death of the wicked. It is the
second coming of Christ that secures the
faith, the the the the fate of the
righteous. And beloved, if we have not
experienced the second coming of Christ
in this temple,
in this heart,
if we are living
still in Egypt,
if we have not experienced the
recreative power of God in our lives, we
are keeping the Sabbath in vain.
what we believe is in vain.
Because
you may know the truth, but if it hasn't
set you free,
you are not free indeed.
So my appeal
today
is to ask the Lord, Lord, help me.
I'm not a Seventh Day Adventist,
but man, if if that's what
if that's what the truth does, lifts me
into heavenly places, gives me a reason
to celebrate God's recreative power in
my If that's what the truth really is
about, Lord, help me to become a seventh
day Adventist. Help me to experience the
second coming in my heart that I may be
ready for the second coming when Jesus
comes again.
And if you are
by name a Seventh Day Adventist because
of what you believe, but you understand
today, woe,
I've only been Seventh Day Adventist in
name but not in character.
Then my appeal to you is Lord
help me not only be to become an
Adventist in name but to be become an
Adventist in character.
Please Lord teach me, help me to make
these doctrinal truths a reflection of
your salvational work in my life.
If that is your desire, I'm going to ask
you to put a one in the chat.
And as I've been saying the last few
weeks, if you want to stand up where you
are to make that commitment that
more earnest to yourself, to the Lord,
stand up where you are. If you need to
stand up, say, "Lord, help me. Help me.
Help me to not just mentally ascend to
the truth, but help me so that the truth
will set me free. Heavenly Father, thank
you for speaking.
Thank you for dropping mana upon us
today. Lord,
thank you for showing us that the truth
is not merely about mental ascent to a
particular way of thinking about the
Bible, but that those truths, Lord, are
designed to teach us practical,
lifechanging,
characterchanging realities.
And Lord, if we have not brought the
truth into the life, if we're only
merely ascending to it, Lord, we do not
yet understand what it means to be a
true follower of you. So Lord, please
forgive us, cleanse us, bless us.
We want to experience
you coming into our hearts even now.
and may everything that comes along with
your coming into our hearts, may that
become a reality in our lives. We thank
you, Lord, for hearing and answering
this prayer because we ask it in Jesus
name. Amen. And amen. I want to thank
you all for tuning in. we're going to
put up on the screen. I'm going to go
ahead and go to my Well, actually, we're
not going to do that because I don't
have it up on my last slide, but um if
you are interested in uh Bible study,
please email um email our Bible worker
at bibleworker living.live.
And um we will put in the link the the
uh in the chat the link for the
afterglow. And so we encourage you to
join us there. And uh there we
fellowship, we talk about the Sabbath
school, we talk about the sermon and
what you've what you've learned and what
you um just your thoughts, your your uh
uh insights and we get just get to
fellowship. So uh please feel free to
join us there. And again, may God bless
you and uh until next Sabbath, may God
keep you and may God give reason for you
to celebrate his working in your life.
Amen.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmanaa.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.